Translation By BaeZZi
자막해석 : BaeZZi
해석이 난해 하더라도 이해를 ^^;
슬랭이 많아서 해석하는데 애 먹었슴
하나!
One
초점을 마쳐!
between the eyes!
Two
둘!
between the eyes.
한방에 보내버려!
- Out!
- What?
아웃!
뭐?!
- She was safe.
- She was out.
- 세이프야
- 아웃이야
She landed right there.
She's safe.
이곳에 밟았으니, 세이프지
Turk: Aw, come on.
그만하쇼, 더이상 듣고 싶지 않으니..
Umpire: That's enough.
I don't want to hear another word.
- You're gone!
- Yeah, I'm gone.
- 퇴장!
- 진정하쇼
할머니께서는 워싱톤에 있는
작은 공원에 날 데려오곤 했었지
My grandmother used to take me
to Washington Square Park...
그때 난 바비 피셔가 한번에
10경기를 하는 걸 보았지
to watch Bobby Fischer
play 10 games at the same time.
Queen me.
여왕
He was five-six moves ahead
on each table.
그는 각 테이블에 다섯번 내지
여섯번 수로 경기를 끝내버렸지
Anyway, he became
the world champ, didn't he?
결국, 그는 챔피언이 되었지,
그가 그랬나?
Then he lost his fucking mind.
암튼, 그리고 나서 정신이 나가 버렸지
He became a raving paranoid.
편집증 환자가 되고 나서,
여기저기서 공격을 받았지
Being attacked
from all directions,
he couldn't see
what was in front of him.
그런 이유로 그를 볼 수가 없었지
Mate. Mate!
장군!
My name is David Fisk,
내 이름은 데이비드 피쉬
Detective First Grade.
1등급 경사
난 30년동안 뉴욕경찰국에서 형사로 있었지
I've been a cop in the NYPD
for over 40 years.
In that time...
그 당시...
I've killed 14 people.
난 14명을 죽였지...
Man: Run that by me
one more time.
다시 틀어보게
I've killed 14 people.
난 14명을 죽였지...
He's nuts.
미쳤군
Turk's voice: When did
these things start?
언제부터 시작된 거지?
How did they start?
어떻게 시작된 거지?
Maybe this one started
with a guy named Charles Randall.
아마도, 찰스 렌달 때문에
이 일이 시작된 것 같다
Randall was a child killer.
렌달은 유아 살해범 이였다
He killed his girlfriend's daughter
4년 전에 그놈은
자기 여자친구의 딸을 죽였다
about four years ago.
Randall: Fuck you, damn asshole.
병신...
Turk's voice: He was tried
for the crime,
그는 기소 되었지만, 배우자 때문에
배심원단으로 부터 무죄를 선고 받았다
but was acquitted
by a jury of his peers.
My partner and I
found this unacceptable.
동료와 난 그 놈 무죄를
수용할 수가 없었다
My partner is a good man.
내 동료는 참 좋은 사람이지
Are you really
gonna do this thing?
자네 정말 그 일을 할 건가?
Do what?
하다니 뭘?
You're going to
take down Randall
자네 지금 렌달을 접수하러 갈게 아닌가?
for a homicide
he didn't commit.
그 놈이 죄를 짓지 않았던
가정 범죄라도..
What am I gonna do?
내가 뭘 하면 좋겠나?
You're my partner.
자넨 나의 동료이고
- You're my role model.
- Right.
나의 마누라일세
- 맞아...
- 마누라 없이 내가 뭘 하겠나?
What am I gonna do
without a role model?
We didn't have
this conversation.
우리가 언제 이런 대화를 한 적이 있는가?
What conversation?
무슨 대화?
Turk's voice: It got done.
이로써 처리했다
Randall lost his freedom
렌달은 짓지도 않은 범죄로
자유를 잃었다
for the crime he didn't commit.
Turk's voice: I lost my faith.
난 신앙을 버렸다
- I'm gonna go.
- Okay.
- 나 가겠네
- 알겠네
You can take this
as a confession if you want.
계속할 지는,
이 고백으로 말미암아....
Whatever.
어찌되었던....
A few weeks ago
things heated up.
그 일이 몇주 전이였지
What do we got on him, Turk?
어떤 자야, 터크?
Marcus Smith, AKA Spider...
big big dope deals,
마커스 스미스 일명'스파이더' 큰 마약 거래상
살인, 갈취, 그 밖에 저질스런 죄질들
murders, extortion,
lots of nice things.
He converted
this old abandoned bank
할렘가에 이 오래된 은행을
404클럽으로 탈바꿈 시켰지
into Club 404 of Harlem.
Maybe when he sees us
he'll confess.
그 놈이 우리에게 자백을 하면 모를까
What, you don't believe
in miracles?
뭐? 자넨 기적을 믿지 않지?
When you pick up a check
one day...
어느날 자네가 수표를 주다면야
기적을 믿겠네
one day,
then I'll believe in miracles.
- Let's go. I'm buying.
- Yeah, that's a miracle I want to see.
- 가세, 내가 한잔 사지..
- 그러세, 그게 바로 내가 원하는 기적일세
♪ We fly high, no lie ♪
♪ You hear that?
You know this, balling ♪
♪ Foreign rides outside ♪
♪ It's like showbiz,
we in the building ♪
♪ We stay fly, no lie... ♪
Turk: This is where he launders
his money.
- 이곳이 바로 돈 세탁을 하는 곳 이군?
- 맞아, 깨끗하게..깨끗하게..
Rooster: Oh, yeah,
cleaning green green green.
Turk: He's all business.
돈 세탁을 깨끗히 하지
I gotta take a leak.
오줌 좀 누고 오겠네
Oh, I'll just be a sec.
몇 분만..
전 오줌 누러온게 아니에요
I'm not peeking.
No problem.
문제 없수다
남자들은 참 편리하죠
- You guys are so lucky.
- Why is that?
뭐가요??
No line to the bathroom and...
남자들은 화장실을 기다리지 않고...
바로 서서 오줌을 누잖아요
You get to pee standing up.
Unzip, psss, zip.
한 방울..한 방울...
싸고나서, 바로 나가잖아요
Badda boom badda bing,
you're out of here.
Yeah, the big guy really outdid himself
on this thing.
난 오줌을 눌 때가,
가장 큰 문제인데...
You want a bump?
좀 드릴까요?
Where did you get that from?
그거 어디서 낫수?
Spider. Supremo.
스파이더, 맛이 끝내주죠
Not bad.
나쁘진 않군
Turk: Not bad?
What the fuck were you looking for?
그래
그럼 뭘 기대했는데?
Come on, Turk,
그래도, 터크,
내 머리를 너무 쌔게 잡았잖아
you pulled my hair.
Gee, my little sister used to
pull my hair harder than that.
내 여동생도 이것 보다는
더 쌔게 잡아당기곤 했지..
Whatever.
그렇군
I gotta go.
가야겠어
- Where the fuck are you going?
- I'm tired.
어디를 가는데?
잠자리에 갈려고
You're tired?
It's America, you whiny bitch.
잠자리에 들려고?
여긴 미국이야
술에 찌든 년아!
Why don't you fucking get in the cab
and do some honest work?
택시 타고 가서 일이나 해
Yeah, she's on her way.
She can't wait to see you.
네, 가고 있는 중입니다
곧 보실 수 있을 겁니다
Rambo the Skateboard Pimp
was my 10th kill.
람보, 이 스케이트 포주가
내 10번째 희생이였지
- Think of me as a street-sweeper.
청소 미화원 처럼...
I cleaned up this worthless
piece of shit
쓰레기 같은 이놈을 깨끗이 해치웠고
은화로 흔적을 남겼지
and left an obituary of sorts.
It rhymes.
시를 지으면서..
Rooster, we gotta find out
who did this.
루스터, 살인자를 찾아야겠어
Give him a medal.
누가 이놈에게 메달을 줬네
Hey, Rambo, you see
who did this?
누가 널 죽였는제 아나, 람보?
He ain't talking, eh?
죽었는데 말을 하겠나?
Real name Robert Brady.
이놈 이름이 "로버트 브래디"였군
Bobby Brady. Damn shame.
바비 브래디, 엿 같군...
What are you thinking?
Marcia? Greg?
어떻게 생각해? 마시아와 그렉?
You guys messing up
my crime scene again?
제 범죄 현장을 망치러 오셨나요?
You don't know
who Bobby Brady is?
"바비 브래디"라고 혹시 아나?
Yeah, we met about an hour ago.
1시간 전에 그를 봤는데
- It looks like close range.
- From the stippling around the wound
프랑스인처럼 생겼어....
네, 상처를 입힌 탄약 점화 상태를 봐선
3피트 거리에서 쐈어요
I'd say two to three feet away.
We'll be fishing fragments
out of his brains.
시체의 머리에서 물고기와 포도주를
꺼내야 될 것 같아요
- What?
- No, I just got that...
- 뭐라고?
- 그래요, 알았어요
"Marcia? Greg?"
That's a good one, Rooster.
"마시아와 그렉"
Well, that was quick.
좋네요, 루스터
빠르군
Just trying to keep pace with you.
전 그냥 당신의 장단에 마췄는데....
Turk: "He trades in sin,
distributes flesh.
그는 찢어진 살집의
죄악을 장사한다
He picks the fruit
when it is fresh.
신선한 과일을 모으면서..
Now someone else
must slap his whore.
지금은 누군가 그놈의 창녀를
때리고 있겠지
His heart has stopped.
He breathes no more."
그의 심장은 멈췄고,
더 이상 숨을 쉬지 않는다
What do you want to do
about this?
자네 이 사건을 어떻게 할 건가?
I say let's make the best of it,
최고의 행동으로 이 사건을
해결해 보고 싶네
canvass the hookers.
Maybe we'll meet one you like.
창녀들이 등장하면,
"자네가 좋아하는 누군가를 만나겠지"
Please. I got all I can handle
from you-know-who.
아니야..제발
자네가 알고 있는 자를 엮이고 싶네
No shit?
농담 말게나
She's got my sperm level so low
I gotta sit down to take a piss.
그녀가 내 굳어진 정액을 먹어서 그런지
앉아서 변기에 똥 때릴네..
Oh, thanks for that picture.
- 오, 묘사해 줘서 고맙네
- 하..내말이 그 말일세
- Hey, what can I tell you?
How can I help you, gentlemen?
뭘 도와드릴까요, 신사분들?
We'd like to talk to you
about your boss.
상사와 이야기 좀 나눴으면 하는데..
He's upstairs.
위 층에 계세요
No, your other boss.
바지 사장 말고 다른 사장
Rambo.
람보...
He is asshole.
그 놈 재수 없어요
Why "he is asshole"?
그 놈이 왜 재수 없는데?
Follow me, please.
절 따라 오세요
You know anybody
who'd want to kill him?
혹시 그를 죽이고 싶어하는 사람이??
Me.
저요
Anyone else?
다른 사람은 없고?
Why? He's dead?
왜요?
그가 죽었나요?
이봐 잘들어, 우리에게 협조하지 않으면
이민국에 연락해서...
Hey, listen, you want to smarten up
and help us out
or am I gonna have to call
somebody at ICE
and have you on the next plane
to kielbasa-land?
당신을 집에 보내 버릴테니..
Go ahead.
한번 해봐요...
전 미국시민 입니다
I am American citizen.
Yeah.
Lick my balls anytime.
여기, 나중에 내 불알 좀 핥아주게
What?
뭐요?
Call us anytime, you know,
뭔가 들었거나 기억이 나면
언제든 전화를 주게 뭐든간에..
if you hear something, anything.
Rooster: I think we're looking
for a guy named Sam the Butcher.
샘 부처란 자를 찾아야겠네
- Who?
누구?
Nah, he's kidding around.
But seriously, Lieutenant,
골때리는 농담이군..
그럼 반장님, 정말로 저희가
람보 살인자의 수사를 맡으란 말이죠?
how far do you want us to go
with this Rambo murder?
I don't know, I was thinking maybe
you could investigate it a bit more,
자네가 조금만 더 조사를 해보면,
누구 짓인지 알게 아닌가...
figure out who did it,
try to put him in jail.
..그 놈을 감옥으로 보내 버려야지
That is, if it doesn't get in the way
of your shuffleboard lessons.
무대뽀로 밀어부치지 않는다면야..
Yeah, no problem.
문제 없수다..
We're also working this dealer Spider
who's tied to these two stiffs
저희가 수사하는 "스파이더"를 꽉 쪼이면
2개의 수사는 잘 해결 되리라 봅니다
we found on Fresh Kills.
If we can nail him, who knows
how far up the ladder it will lead?
그 놈에게 접근해서,
누군가 그놈의 거짓말을 알고 있겠죠
So what about it?
그래서 어떻게 할텐가?
I popped this lawyer
with an ounce of blow.
시원하게 한방 갈기고 있는데,
그녀가 코로 들이키면서 보여 주던데
She practically shoved it up my nose.
I got her to flip on him.
난 그 놈에게 놀랐거든
Lucky fuck, eh?
운이 좋군..
She scored it from him directly?
- 그녀가 그 놈으로부터 마약을 구입했나?
- 네
- Yeah, she did.
- Good.
좋아
Okay, well, get what you can out of her
and kick her loose.
그 놈이 주체하지 못하게 방법을
강구하고 나서, 잡아 들여
I hate trying to prosecute
fucking lawyers.
빈둥거리는 변호사를
잡아 두는게 영 내키지 않는군
- This isn't Spider's club.
- The back way in.
이곳은 스파이더 클럽이 아닌데..
뒷뜰로 가면 돼
Rooster: Yeah, it's an abandoned
linen factory, Jessica.
음, 이곳은 황폐해져 버린 공장이지, 제시카
I guess I'm not your average...
제가 하는 역활이....
뭐라고 불리죠?
what do you call it?
- 밀고자
- 경찰 끄나풀
- Rat?
- Stoolie?
Thanks.
고맙네요
I mean, I think usually
it's some poor African-American kid
가난한 아프리카 미국인들은
이곳에서 마약에 찌들거나 매춘을 하던데..
or a junkie or a prostitute.
Well, normally 200-grand-a-year
corporate lawyers
200명 정도 클럽에 있는 그 새끼들은..
are much smarter than your average
African-American junkie whore...
...흑인과 미국의 술취한 창녀보다는
더 똑똑하지
normally, but sometimes
they only think they are.
일반적으로,
그들은 늘 그렇게 생각하며 살지
Man over radio: It's all set
on this end.
모든 준비가 완료 됐습니다
Are you guys sure
it's safe in there?
그곳은 안전한가?
Man: You tell your girlfriend
to grow a pair and let's go.
여자 친구에게 긴장하라고 하세요
이제 갑니다..
What do you say, Counsel?
Are you ready to do this thing?
"영사"라고 말했나?
준비 되었지?
Yeah, let's get it over with.
네, 어서 끝내버립시다
Okay, remember what we said?
You go in there,
좋아, 우리 대기 할테니, 그곳으로 가서
뭘 필요한지 묻기 전까지는 기다려..
you wait for him to ask you
for what you need, right?
And then you don't come back here
with less than four ounces.
110그램(4온스) 이하로는 사지 않는다고 해
- Four ounces?
- Yeah.
- 110그램 이요?
- 응
Isn't that a lot? I, like, buy a couple
of balls at the club, that's it.
많지 않나요?
전 적게 사는 편인데..
You just say you're going skiing and
you need a week's worth of fresh powder.
스키를 타기 위해 1주일치 달라고 하면 돼
Yeah, you tell him you're going
on vacation.
그래, 휴가 때문에 필요하다고 해
I do this thing
and my record's wiped clean?
이 일을 할께요..
그럼 제 범죄기록이 모두 삭제가..?
As a whistle.
전부는 안되고..
No one at my law firm will know
that I got busted, right?
법률 회사에 알리진 않을 거죠, 네?
It never happened.
그런 일은 절대 없을 거야
Look, Counsel, we all know you
better than this.
눈 한번 딱 감고 이일을 해주면 돼..
You just do this, you stop
shoving that shit up your nose,
다시는 마약하지 말고, 집에 가서..
you go home, you get married,
you have kids,
결혼도 하고...아이들도 낳고..
다시는 이곳에 발 들이지 마
you never come back here,
and that's that.
Yeah.
알겠어요
Officer: Everybody's in position.
- Turk: Okay, we're going.
- Officer: Yes, sir.
좋아, 가자고..
네!
Officer: Let's push the signal
back 50%.
Rooster: Hey, Jessica.
제시카!
Break a leg.
행운을 빌어
It's two flights down.
2층으로 내려가시면..
문은 왼쪽이고, 초인종을 누르면 돼요
The door's on the left.
Ring the bell.
Hey, Stubby, why don't you
go and escort our company up here?
이봐 스투비,
가서 고객을 모셔와..
Go on, fat boy.
서둘러, 뚱땡아
Get it on.
시작해 보자고..
- Good afternoon.
- Hey, Spider.
안녕하슈
안녕, 스파이더
- I'll be downstairs.
- All right.
- 전 계단에 있을게요
- 알았어
- How are you?
- All right, baby,
- 잘 지내죠?
- 네, 제시카..
just checking out this wizard shit
before I let my kids watch it.
이거 제 자식들이 보던 걸
보는 중이라서..이 영화 보신적 있죠?
- You seen this?
- No.
아뇨
The guy is a stone dealer.
I let my little ones watch this...
"저놈들과 거래하지 마세요",
마약쟁이들은 알아서 유통 시키죠
they'll all turn out junkies.
You know what I'm saying?
무슨 말인지 알죠?
He's got a point.
저놈 일리가 있네
- You remember Underdog?
- What about him?
- 자네 "언더독" 영화 기억하나?
- 무슨 개?
That fucking dog spawned
a generation of junkies.
아~ 그 개새끼,
마약쟁이들을 대량 살포하는 개새끼..
So you converted the bank
into a club and a recording studio?
이 오래된 은행안에 클럽과
녹음 스튜디오를 만든 거네요?
- Yeah. You like it?
- Yeah.
- 네, 맘에 들어요?
- 네
What are you talking about?
뭔 소리를 하는 거지?
What did Underdog do
all the time?
뭐긴 그 동안 줄곧 개소리지..
He was always shining shoes
신발을 닦고 있군..
and whenever Sweet Polly Purebred
would call out to him,
그 순종인 "Sweet Polly"가 남자에게 소리치면,
개가 듣고나서 남자가 여자를 구출하지
his dog ears would pick it up
and he'd rescue her.
Yeah, but what did he do
when he needed his super strength?
그럼 강력한 힘이 필요할 때,
그는 뭘 하고 있었지? 반지를 끼던가?
He'd go to his ring, remember?
Pull out a pill, pop it.
알약을 내 뱉고, 그걸 터트리지
Holy shit, you're right.
He was a little fucking speed freak.
빌어먹을, 자네 말이 맞아
그 놈은 자네에게 병신같이 지껄이지..
Spider: So what's the business?
그럼 원하는게 뭐죠?
How about a QP?
You're good for a QP.
QP는 어때요?
QP가 좋긴 하죠
The fuck you want with QP?
QP는 허벌라게 오래가죠
I'm going skiing with friends,
친구들과 스키타러 갈려고요
a lot of friends.
친구들이 많거든요
- Where?
- Aspen, Colorado.
어디를?
콜로라도의 아스펜요
Shit. I'm sure you can
score one in Aspen.
제기랄..
묻기 전에 당신에게 좀 보여드리죠
Not your primo brand.
멋지군요
You ski?
- 위스키?
- 네..
Sure. My whole life.
Come on, I don't have all day.
제발요, 꾸물거릴 시간이 없어요
Why don't you put down your jacket,
stay a little while?
상의를 벚고, 잠시 기달려요
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나?
Jessica: Actually,
I've got to run.
사실은 서둘러야 해요
1시간 안에 중요한 기업공개 일이 있어서...
I have a major IPO
closing in an hour, so...
You know, stress will kill you.
You gotta chill out.
갑자기 떨리나 보죠,
알려주죠..
I'm as chill as I get.
정말로 전......
What do you want to do?
어떻게 할 건가?
You know, every once in a while...
도청기를 숨긴 걸 내가 모를 줄 아나?
one of you Upper East Side bitches
gets popped,
넌 정말 재수 없는 년이야,
나 같이 흉악한 검둥이를 만나서 말야
tries to to roll over
on a nigga like me.
You're scared now.
지금 무서운가 보지?
Looks like the cavalry
come to rescue you.
널 구출하러 경찰들이 등장하셨군
Can I help you, gentlemen?
뭘 도와드릴까요? 경찰나리들..
Yeah, let us in, Spider.
어서 문 열어, 스파이더
I'm sorry, there's no one here
by that name.
그런 이름은 이곳에 없는데..
- Let us in.
- We only want to talk to you.
- 어서 문 열게
- 자네와 이야기 할 게 있으니 문 열게
See, I know how to look
and I know where to look.
보이지, 어떻게 날 감시하는지
어디서 날 감시하고 보는지
난 다 알거든
Come to papa.
아빠에게 오렴..
It always hurts the first time.
처음에는 항상 아프기 마련이지
Turk: You all right?
괜찮아?
Why wouldn't she be all right?
We're watching TV.
왜 이 여자에게 도움을 주는데?
TV만 봤을뿐이야
How the fuck is she gonna get hurt
watching TV?
TV 시청 때문에,
어디 다치기라도 했나 보지?
She could have seen or heard
something that scared her.
- 그녀가 무언가 겁내는 걸 내가 들었어
- 듣다니 뭘?
- Like what?
- Like some big fucking mutt
병신같이 터프한 척 하고
돼지같은 입술을 가진 개 새끼..
shooting his bug fat
fucking mouth off.
Wasn't nobody here fitting that description
till a minute ago.
그래요?
1분전 까지는 그런 사람이 없었지만..
I'm gonna show you ugly,
you fucking mother...
내가 함 보여줄까? 못생긴 개새꺄..
- We've said enough.
- Oh, you finna bring your wife up in here?
- 이만하면 됐네
- 그러면, 자네 아내를 이곳에 데려오지?
That's it. That's it.
Let's go. It's okay.
그만하세, 가세...가자고
됐네...
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay. I'm okay.
- 그만하게?
- 알았수
- 괜찮아
- 도청기 돌려 받고 싶수?
You want your wire back?
Firearm!
총이야!
No, Stubby, no!
안돼, 스투비, 하지마!
Get down.
Get the fuck down!
엎드려! 엎드리라고!
Turk: Come on.
가자고!
The fat one's dead.
뚱땡이는 죽었네
Well, that went well.
저 잘했죠?
Oh, shit, you're bleeding.
오 이런, 피를 흘리고 있네
4-4 squad, Central.
11-41, request ambulance.
3-4분대는 본부에 연락해서
앰블런스를 부르게
I need EMS. Subject shot,
184th and St. Nicholas.
니클라스 184가에 총상을 입은 사람이 있으니,
EMS(응급 서비스)가 필요함
Really, I tried my best.
- 제가 할수 있는 최선을 다...
- 이제 곧 괜찮아 질 거야, 귀염둥이, 괜찮아..
You're doing just fine, Counsel.
You're doing just fine. Just relax.
Hey, guys, if you ever
need a lawyer...
편히 있어..
저기, 형사분들..
변호사가 필요 하시면.....
Yeah, okay.
You bet.
In good old days
we used to
옛날이 그리운가 보지!
let the perp bleed out
and call off the ambulance.
앰블런스를 부르기 전에,
우린 널 이곳에 잠재울 거야
- Calm calm calm.
- Fucking lowlife.
- 진정, 진정하게...
- 비열한 개새끼
You made your point.
그만하면 됐네, 그만하게
Tough little bitch, ain't you,
kicking a man while he's handcuffed?
당신 너무 터프한데, 안그래?
수갑을 채운 날 발로 차버리고..
Shut the fuck up,
you piece of shit.
입닥쳐, 개노무 새끼야!
You think I won't blow
your fucking head off?
네 머리를 못 날릴 것 같나?
I wouldn't think twice
about it.
난 2번 생각하지 않아
I'd go in there,
get the fat boy's gun,
저쪽에 가서, 저 돼지의 총을 가지고 와서
너에게 주면 그만이야
come back here
and put two between your eyes.
한방에 보내 버리면 돼
Where's EMS?
앰블런스는 안오나?
Woman: This thing was a clusterfuck
to end all clusterfucks.
이번 사건은 엉망이에요
모든 지원 부대가 엉망이야
You got nothing.
아무것도 얻은 게 없습니다
How about felony murder?
그 살인자를 찾은 건 어때요?
No drugs, right?
So no predicate felony,
마약도 없고, 마약 중독자도 아니고,
음모도 없고, 나올게 전혀 없어요
no conspiracy,
no nothing.
No felony. No felony.
I can't believe this.
중죄가 아니라면....믿을 수가 없군
차라리 중죄라고 말하는 건 어때요?
No felony.
How do you spell felony?
Homicide, racketeering, drugs...
I mean, what are we talking about?
할렘가 현장, 폭력배, 마약들..
그럼 이게 중죄가 아닙니까?
Hey, you're lucky
that white girl didn't die.
이봐요, 형사님은 그 백인 여자가
죽지 않은 걸 다행으로 여기라고요!
IAB is gonna interview
both of you
IAB에서 두분을 심문 할 겁니다
앞으로 2주 안에 보고서를 제출하세요
and do a preliminary report
over the next couple of weeks.
Now off the record
you actually didn't violate procedure
지금은 비공개지만...
당신은 사실 소송 절차를 위반하지 않았지만,
because the victim had a firearm
aimed at you,
사상자가 먼저 총을 쐈고,
형사분들이 대응을 했으니 됐습니다
so if you stick together
you should make it through this.
그래서 두분 사이가 좋다면,
이 사건을 잘 해결하겠죠
Lieutenant: You'd better get
your story straight too,
자네들 있는 그대로 객관적으로
말하는 게 좋을 걸세
'cause I'm not going back to Far Rockaway
because you two fucked up.
난 저 멀리 전근을 가기 싫으니..
자네 둘이 일을 망쳤으니...
And you're gonna spend some couch time
with the rubber-gun squad.
자네 둘은 집에서 발이나 딲고
"Rubber Gun Squad"영화나 보게 될 걸세
And you'd better take this shrink seriously
or you'll be off active duty.
자네들 정신과 의사 상담을 받지 않으면
이번 임무에서 빠지게 될 걸세
That fucking piece of shit
just walks.
그 놈들은 자기 마음대로 하는군
Knock it off, Turk.
입 닥치게, 터크!
Relax, partner.
He's gonna get his.
진정하게, 파트너..
반장님 일이 꼬일테니...
Man: Gentlemen, your questions.
여러분,
질문 하겠습니다
- Who made the decision to enter?
- I did.
그 시간에 출동 하라고
누가 결정을 내렸습니까?
- Whose decision was it to enter?
- Mine.
내가 그랬수
- 마지막 총격은 누가 했죠?
- 내가 그랬수
Did you immediately identify yourselves
as police officers?
- 그 즉시 경찰 신분을 밝혔나요?
- 그렇수, 그렇게 했지
- Yes, we did.
- Did you immediately identify yourselves?
당신들은 정말로 경찰 신분을 밝혔나요?
The informant's position
was becoming untenable.
밀고자의 현 상황이 위험해서
말할 처지가 아니였수다
- We were afraid she was in danger.
- Turns out you were right.
- 당신들 주장이 옳은 것 같군요
- 당신들은 돼지들이야
- No fucking kidding, nine-to-fiver.
- Excuse me, Detective?
- 저기요, 형사?
- 제 고객과 이야기 끝났나요?
Are you finished
with my client?
- They're like Lennon and McCartney.
- Not an inch of daylight between them.
저 둘은 안성기와 박중훈 같군
거짓말은 아닌 것 같아
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나?
Nothing there.
건질게 없네
They endangered the informant.
We can't make them wrong on that.
밀고자를 위험에 빠지게 했지만,
총을 봤고, 그에 맞는 대항을 했으니..
They saw a gun, they reacted.
They beat the fuck
out of the suspect,
터크가 그 얼간이를 차긴 했지만,
그가 잘못을 저지른 건 아니지
but he's not filing charges.
Let's see what the shrink says.
정신과 의사가 뭘 말할지 보세나
So what are we gonna
do now, Doc?
그럼, 지금 뭘 물어 볼거요? 의사양반
확실한 범인을 잡기 위해선...
Are we gonna find out
if I'm sane enough
총 갖고 다니지 말고
범인들을 뒤쫓으라는 말씀?
to carry a gun,
chase bad guys?
Okay, why did you become a cop?
당신은 왜 경찰이 되었나요?
Well, it was New Year's Eve.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
그게, 뉴욕의 크리스마스 전날 밤에
경찰이 되리라고 마음 먹었죠
I didn't have the same opportunities
you had, Dr. Prosky.
지금은 말할 시기가 적절하지 않소,
프로스키 의사양반
Where I come from
it was either a gun and a badge
제 고향에서는 총과 경찰배지는..
or a hard hat and a hammer.
안전모와 망치로 통하죠..
How do you feel
when you fire your weapon?
총을 쏠 때의 기분은 어떤가요?
It's like Dirty Harry said...
"There's nothing wrong
더티 해리가 말하길 :
선량한 사람들이 총을 맞는 한,
약간의 총질은 아무런 문제가 없다고..
with a little shooting as long as
the right people get shot."
Prosky: And when the wrong people
get shot?
그럼 범죄인들이 총 맞거나....?
엿 같은 소리죠..
Turk: It sucks, but I'd rather be in it
that out of it.
배지를 단 경찰이라면 마지막 부분에서
오히려 끝낼 수 있으면 끝내야죠
There's nothing worse
than being stuck on a bench.
How do you feel when you see
innocent people get killed?
무죄인 사람들이 죽으면
느낌이 어떻소?
You know...
그게 사실......
I sort of get numb to it.
일종에 정신이 멍해지죠
Here.
여기..
I want you to take this.
당신에게 이걸 주고 싶소
Use it to jot down your thoughts,
your questions,
이 메모장에 당신의 생각, 질문, 그리고
당신 자신이 참고할 만한 것들을 적어 두시요
anything you may have noticed
about yourself,
whatever.
아무튼..
I won't ask for it.
그거에 대해 물어 보지는 않겠소
Just for you.
당신을 위해서니..
I want you to try it.
함 해보시오
Sounds like fun.
재미 있겠군
Harder.
Go, Turk, go!
뛰어, 터크, 뛰어!
You got third.
Go go!
어서 뛰어!
어서! 뛰어!
Yeah!
Look at that.
좋았어!
바로 그거야!
You own it. You own it.
자네가 이겼네!
No matter what they say
about you,
그들이 쓴 소리해도
귀담아 듣지 말게나!
you're tremendous!
자넨 훌륭하니깐!
Go go, Turk, go!
뛰어, 터크!
뛰어!
Safe.
You dropped the ball.
세이프! 공을 떨어 뜨렸네!
- A fucking cheap shot, man.
- Get away from the bag.
- 이게 무슨 비열한 플레이요!
- 정단한 플레이야!
- Or what? Or what? Or what?
- Watch the bag.
- 그래서 뭐요? 뭐요?...
- 공친 후에 달렸어
아니면 어쩌라고!
누군 배짱이 없는 줄 알아!!
나도 배짱은 있어!
뉴욕 경찰들 대개는 욕구 불만,
적대 행위, 그리고 남성호르몬 넘치기에..
Turk's voice: The NYPD is bubbling
with frustration,
hostility and testosterone,
ready to erupt
at any moment.
그리고 언제 어느 때나
싸울 준비가 되어 있다
Think of me
as the release valve.
방아쇠를 당기고, 혈압이 내려가도,
분리된 영혼이 날 붙잡아도 말야
One flick of the trigger
and the pressure goes down.
You know why
you join the force?
폭력이 왜 즐거운지 아는가?
To get respect.
존경을 받기 위해서지!
Most people respect the badge.
대부분 사람들은
경찰 배지를 존경하지
Everybody respects the gun.
모든 사람들은 총을 존경하지!
Hey, Riley, I was talking to JD...
이봐 라일리, 난 JD에게 이야기 했는데..
자네들은 필립 트래거란 새끼를 잡았던데?
you guys caught a stiff named
Phillip Trager, a gun-runner?
총포 밀수입자 던가?
Oh, yeah, a real piece of shit.
- 네, 정말 똥같은 새끼죠
- 어떻게 굴복 시켰나?
- How did that go down?
- I don't know.
몰라요, 누군가 그 놈에게
약을 맛 보라고 준 것 같은데..
Somebody gave him a taste
of his own medicine, I guess,
walked right into his apartment,
killed him with one of his own guns.
한 남자가 그 놈의 아파트 주소를 알려줘서,
총으로 그 놈을 죽였죠
Did the shooter leave a note
or anything?
총을 쏜 놈 말야, 혹시 아는 거라도?
Yeah, actually,
the shooter left a poem.
네, 사실 범인이 시를 남겼는데..
He did?
No shit.
남겼다고?
오 이런..!
Yeah. Hey, Simon,
사이몬, 혹시..그 시 기억나나?
you remember that poem
from the Trager case?
트래거 사건?
What are you doing, man?
- 너 지금 뭔 소리하는 거야?
- 터크가 그거에 대해 물어봐서..
Turk's asking about it.
What the hell are you doing?
도대체 무슨 말을 했길래..
? Que mierda 'tas haciendo ahi, papa?
No le digas mierda a eso loco.
Riley: Calmate. He wants to hear
about the poem.
저기.. 터크가 그 시에 대해 알고 싶데
"Merchant of thieving class,
넌 마약 거래를
너무 많이 했기에..
I slit his throat
and capped his ass.
내가 너의 지저분한 문을 따 버린다
I took his gun, I took his...
그가 촘을 잡으니...
I took his life, I took his gun,
But too bad he's not the only one."
난 그를 죽이고 총을 잡았지만,
그게 좋은것 만이 아니다
That's how it goes,
something like that.
그게 바로 제가 아는 시 내용의 전부죠
2운체는 아니지만, 시적이죠
It's not iambic pentameter,
but it rhymes.
- Rooster.
- Yo.
- 루스터!
- 왜!
We're looking for the same guy.
우리가 찾는 범인과 동일하군,
람보를 죽인 범인과 말야..
He knocked off a pimp named Rambo
a few weeks ago. When was yours?
몇주 전, 브루스 프라이저에서..
언제 그 사건을 맡았나?
Last week. We're running ours with the ATF
because of the guns.
지난 주, 총 사건 때문에 저희들
ATF[화기 단속국]에 명부에 올라 때쯤..
We're back in business on the Rambo case.
Looks like the same guy knocked off
람보, 수사에 뒷받침이 되겠어
지난 3주, 총포를 죽인 범인과
우리가 수사하는 범인과 동일 인물이야
- a gun dealer on the three-three last week.
- No shit.
오, 그렇군!
- What do you mean? That's our case.
- That's our case. You're taking our case.
- 수사에 뒷받침이 되겠다니요?
- 그건 저희 사건 입니다
지금 저희들 사건을 뺏어 가실려고...
Seniority, guys.
Tag along, you'll learn something.
그 사건 손떼게,
자네들은 아직 배우는 입장이야
Oh, tell me the guy's name
is Greg Brady.
자네들 그 놈 이름이
"그레이트 그래디"라고 말 해줘
Please. It is, isn't it?
제발, 그렇지? 아닌가?
오, 누군가 브래디를 한방 치겠는데
Oh, somebody's knocking off
the Brady Bunch.
Gotta be the Partridge Family.
아니면 작은 주머니를
잡을려고 애쓰겠지
Turk's voice: Trager,
a gun-runner bites the dust...
트래거, 총포 화약의 밀수입자,
11번 째로 죽은 희생자
number 11.
Karen: The bullet matched the.45
in Trager's apartment.
총알이 트래거 아파트에 발견한
45구경 총과 일치해요
That was no surprise.
So I ran it through ATF.
놀랄 일은 아니지만....
그래서 ATF[화기 단속국]에 뒤져봤죠
It's one of a batch of six
that was stolen from a gun shop
총알은 6개의 한 묶음이고,
지난 달, 한 중학생에게 털렸다고 했어요
- in Virginia last month.
- Yeah, probably by Trager.
그럼, 트래거가 확실하군
That's what they think.
He matches the description they have.
그건 그들의 생각이고,
그들의 서술은 그와 일치하죠
It still doesn't help us find the guy.
It just helps us tie him to the victims,
이놈을 찾더라도,
아직까지는 도움이 안되겠군
그냥 사건 시간만 알 뿐이고,
그 시간에 범인은 이미 시를 쓴거군
which he's already doing
with his little fucking poems.
- Excuse me. Hello.
여보쇼
Hey, Turk, don't forget
we got a court date later.
이봐 터크, 잊지 말게나
우리 나중에 법정에 가야 하네
So...
그러면...
I heard he kicked the shit
out of that dealer you guys took down.
그 마약쟁이를 쏘고,
제압했다고 들었는데..
Spider.
아, 스파이더..
So?
그래서 뭐?
그가 그랬나요?
Did he?
Yeah, he got him
down on the ground.
맞아, 땅 바닥에 그를 제압했지....
The guy was handcuffed.
수갑이 체워진 채로...
And he just started
kicking him in the gut.
터크가 그 놈을 제압하고 나서,
발로 찼었지
And then
그리고 나서...
he gets down on the guy's chest
그 놈 가슴을 누르고...
and he really starts smacking him
정말로 때리더군
hard in the face over and over
머리 위 부분을...계속해서...
and screaming at the top
of his lungs,
배와 폐에 소리나도록...
"네놈 머리를 산산조각 낸다고, 개노무 새끼야"
"I'm gonna break
your fucking face,
you little bitch!"
Then his eyes really started
to fill up.
그리고 나서 그 놈 눈에서 피 눈물이 나더군..
그 놈을 그렇게 하고 나서...
I mean, they get dark...
터크는 "흑인"을 그렇게 다루면서..
you know how he gets
the sort of rage in him.
그 놈에게 분노를 표출 하더군
I thought he was gonna
kill this guy.
난 터크가 그를 죽이는 줄 알았어
Really?
정말요?
You're a bad little girl.
자넨 정말 나쁜 여자야
Hmm?
- I got work to do.
- You bet.
저 일하러 갈께요
못됐군
Woman: Counselor,
my hands are tied here.
판결을 하겠습니다
법적인 증거가 없는 한,
이 재판을 판결을 하기가 어렵군요
Without a secure
chain of custody,
any evidence obtained
after the initial search
후에 발생한 어떠한 증거들은
배제 할 것입니다..
- must be excluded.
- You gotta be fucking kidding me.
말도 안되는 소리군..
Therefore I am forced
to grant defense
따라서, 저는 미스터 벤렉트씨의
강제 성폭행인 혐의에 대해...
motion to dismiss
all charges
of rape and assault
against Mr. Van Luytens.
기각하는 바 입니다
- Your Honor.
- Judge: You think I want this guy
재판장님
검사! 피고인이 내 딸 근처에
오기를 나도 원하는 줄 아나?
going anywhere
near my daughter,
그렇지 않으면, 어느 누구의 딸이라도?
or anyone's daughter
for that matter?
You messed up.
I am unleashing your client
난 피고인을 풀어줄 수 밖에 없네
아니면 곧 재판이 다시 재개 되겠지
unto the world.
I'm sure we'll all be
back here again very soon.
Look at him.
Look at this motherfucker.
보게
저 개노무 새끼를 봐...
Hey, it's gonna come back to you, mutt.
You're gonna get it.
이봐, 경고하나 해 주지
네놈을 잡고야 말겠어
- When you walk outside watch your back.
- Easy, Turk.
밖에서 길을 걷고 있을 때,
항상 뒤를 조심해
Order in my court.
조용히 하세요!
- Okay, mutt? You fucking mutt.
- Not here, not now.
- 너 같은 개새끼는..
- 이러지 말게나, 지금은 아닐세..
Not here, not now.
Will you get him out of here
당신 고객에게 헛튼소리 하기 전에,
저놈을 여기서 밖으로 끌어내게
before somebody passes a sentence
on him you can't appeal?
Order!
- 정숙! 정숙!
- 무슨 말인지 알았으면, 사라져
- You know what I mean? Go go.
- Order, Detective.
형사!
Turk's voice: Dr. Prosky suggested
that I free-associate.
정신과 의사인 프로스키는
내가 자유를 연상 시킨다고 한다
So here I go.
그래서, "내가 간다"
You know what I think about
when I pull a trigger?
방아쇠를 땡길 때,
내가 무슨 생각을 할까?
- I think about the Infield Fly Rule.
난 내야 플라이로 날아가는 생각을 한다
그 규칙이 좋다
I love that fucking rule.
It assumes the worst in everybody.
모두에게는 최악이라고 할순 있겠지
It says, "Sorry, batter, you're a schmuck
for popping up with runners on.
"미안하네, 자네는 내야 플라이를 친
얼간이야..허나 주자는 달린다"
And you, stupid-ass infielder,
you don't get to cheat
"사기꾼을 잡아" 소리를 치는 멍청한 내야수는,
공을 떨어뜨리면, 그걸 바로 탈출이라고 불린다
and drop the ball just because
you caught a break."
My favorite part...
the batter's out
내가 좋아하는 부분은 타자가 "아웃" 되는 거다
그러나 주자는 목숨을 걸고 나아간다
but the runners advance
at their own risk.
Well, isn't this
a pleasant surprise?
그럼, 불괘한 기분이 들지 않을까?
Turk's voice: That's the way
life should be.
원래 그래야 하기 때문에,
너같은 새끼는 각오를 단단해 해야 하...
You can be a motherfucker
at your own risk.
Or not.
Van Luytens... one less rapist.
거나, 아니거나..
반 루이텐스, 강간범이 하나 줄어든다
누가 이놈을 그리워 하지?
Who's gonna miss him?
Nobody.
Number 12 and counting.
아무도..
숫자를 세면서..12번 희생자
Whoa whoa, hot coffee.
오오...조심해요
- Good morning, Detective Riley.
- Hey, good morning.
- 안녕하세요, 형사님
- 좋은 아침
- Door on your left.
- Any signs of forced entry?
왼쪽에 계십니다
- 강제로 들어갔나?
- 그건 아니고, 페레즈 형사님이 계십니다
Doesn't look like it.
Detective Perez is in there.
He's in there already?
All right.
벌써 와 있다고? 알았네
- Hey, how about those Mets last night?
- Yeah, how about 'em?
- 지난 밤에 경기들 어땠나?
- 네, 예상한 대로요..
Hey, Teddy, Teddy, come here,
check this out.
이봐 테디, 테디, 이쪽으로 오게
이걸 함 봐봐
Wow.
Fuck.
- Oh my God.
- That's big.
젠장
크네
And powerful.
힘이 넘치지
- What, a plasma screen?
- LCD.
- 플라즈마 맞나?
- 아니, CT
- That's plasma.
- No, it's got to be LCD.
- 플라즈마야
- 아니, CT가 맞아, 봐.....
- Perez: It wouldn't be that big.
- Hey, guys, guys.
- 이봐요
- 크지 않은 것 같은데
형사님들!
He was shot at close range,
dropped right here.
이 남자 근거리에서 사살 당했어요
The pussy doesn't look like he put up
much of a fight, does he, Karen?
여자들은 싸움을 잘하는 놈을 좋아 하던데,
그렇지 않아, 카렌?
Nothing to indicate that
그렇게 보이지 않은데
in terms of struggle.
No forced entry, cuts, bruises.
싸움은 순식간 이지,
힘 안들이고, 절단 내고, 상처를 내지
Hey, nobody wants to hear
about your private life, Officer Corelli.
이봐 코렐리 경찰관,
당신 사생활에 다들 관심 없어
That's detective to you,
Officer Needledick.
그건 당신 생각이죠,
니들딕 형사님
- Ooh.
- Perez: Ouch.
- Looks like it's our guy again.
- Who did you get this time?
저희가 뒤쫓는 동일 범인이죠
이번 희생자는 누군데?
This is Jonathan Van Luytens.
두개 정도의 차 대리점을 소유한,
존 루이텐스 입니다
He owns a couple
of car dealerships.
- Oh, shit.
- He was up on rape charges,
- 오 이런
- 강간혐의는 있었지만, 지난 주에 풀려 났어요
but they got tossed out
last week.
Look at this.
이걸 읽어봐요
"A man devoid of all respect,
Of beauty, charm or intellect,
남자는 전쟁을 피하고,
미모를 존경한다
그가 먹었던 늙은 요염한 여자들은..
He took what women
would not give.
...유죄를 선고하지 않을 것이다,
삶을 살 권리조차 없었다
He didn't have
the right to live."
That's our boy all right.
이거 그 놈이지, 맞나?
Looks like he had a beef
with our old pal Jonny.
이놈 시는 늙은
"팔 조니" 보다 우위에 있네
You know him?
그를 아세요?
Both: Yeah.
그럼
He's one slippery
son of a bitch, let me tell you.
그는 나약하고 감상적인 새끼지,
라고 말하고 싶네
Turk: Yeah.
Lieutenant: You guys know how much
fun it is to not catch a serial killer?
자네들은 연속 살인범을 보고만
있는 걸 즐거운가 보군?
You got a point here, Lieutenant?
좋은 지적입니다, 반장님
The point is
지적은 말야...
you'd better both
think seriously
자네들이 이 사건을 지휘하든 안 하든 간에,
진지하게 수사 했으면 하네
about whether or not
you want the lead on this case.
You don't think
we're up to this?
저희가 하지 않는다고 보십니까?
Come on, you got what,
이거 왜 이래
about 110 years on the job
between the two of you?
자네 둘이 이곳에서 근무한 년수가
110년 이라도 된단 말인가?
- 120.
120년 입니다
I'm telling you, you screw it up
badly enough,
한 마디 하겠는데, 자네들은 나사가 풀렸어
자네들 연금 받고 싶지 않은가 보군
they may try to fuck you
out of your pension.
You want to risk that?
그런 위험을 감수하고 싶은가?
- Yeah.
- Fuck, yeah.
- 네
- 그렇고 말고요
406, Lieutenant. 406.
406 입니다, 반장님
Okay, 406...
what does that mean?
좋아, 406 의미가 뭔데?
Ted Williams.
테드 윌리암스
(전설의 보스턴 레드삭스 야구선수)
Ted Williams, the last day of the season,
is batting 400.
테드 윌림암스는 맨 마지막 시즌에
타율이 400을 달성 했죠..
Sox manager wants to bench him,
protect his average, right?
삭스 매니저는 그에게 평균치
장려금을 보상했죠, 맞죠?
Williams plays
both games anyway,
그는 2개의 경기를 더 뛰며,
마침내 6을 더한 타율이 406 되었죠
goes six for eight,
ends up at 406...
the last guy that ever hit
over 400.
Okay, fine. It's all yours.
좋아, 자네들 세상이야
Just don't go moaning to me
when some traffic cop
그저 불평만 하지 말게나, 그리고 어느..
교통 경찰관이 그 살인범의 속도 위반 때문에
차를 세우면, 그 놈은 15분을 영광으로 알겠지
pulls your serial killer over
for speeding
and he grabs your
15 minutes of fame and you realize
자네들은 "어라, 이 살인자 새끼가
내 앞에 있을수 있겠다" 라고 진짜라고 느끼겠지
the asshole could have been
standing right there in front of you
and it would have taken you
1000 light years to nail him.
그리고 그놈을 잡기 위해선
1천 광년이 걸리겠지
Not for nothing, Lieutenant,
거슬릴진 모르지만, 반장님
수 광년은 시간이 아닌 거리를 의미하죠
light years measures distance,
not time.
Well, thank you, Detective.
I'll make a note of that.
고맙네, 형사나리
참조 하겠네
Ellis Lynde, 2004.
2003년 엘리스 린드
This guy had a history
of cruising gay bars,
이 남자는 게이 술집을 들락날락 거리며
20명과 떡을 치고, 그들을 허벌라게 때렸죠
picking up twinkies,
beating the shit out of them.
Lynde was found shot dead
in his apartment.
그리고 나서 그의 아파트에서
총을 맞은 채로 발견 되었죠
Whoever's doing this
gets up real close to the guys,
그들 중 한명이 이 남자와
떡을 치고 있었죠
blows their brains out
without any trouble,
그의 머리는 구멍이 났죠,
아무런 소리 없이...
leaves no fingerprints
지문도 없었고, 분명한 사실은....
and obviously
takes pride in his work.
그의 거실에서 사건이 일어났죠
Okay, what could be
murder number two back from '04,
그러면 2004년 이후에 시작된
2번째 살인이 될겁니다
one Matthew Mitrella.
Turk's voice: I was shaking
the first couple of times
나는 냉혹하게도 살인한 것에..
처음엔 한 두 차례나 몸을 떨고 있었다
I killed in cold blood.
I kept thinking if I got caught
they'd kick me off the force.
감기 때문이라 생각했지만,
그 힘이 날 뺏아갈 거라 생각했다...
I wasn't worried about prison,
but losing the gun and the shield...
난 감옥에 가는 걸 두려워 하지 않았지만,
총과 탄피를 뺏기는 게 두려웠다
that scared me.
I went into work the next day
expecting to feel different.
다음날 난 출근을 했다
그들이 다른 기분을 느끼는 걸 예상했다
I thought everybody would look at me
the way cops look at civilians
경찰의 비열한 행위를 시민들이 알고 있다면,
그들도 날 그런 모습으로 볼 꺼라고 생각했지만..
and know which ones are dirty.
But they didn't.
That's when I knew
그들은 하지 않았다
그 순간 알게 되었다
이 일을 계속할 수 있다고...
I could keep on
doing this forever.
...영원히
Turk's voice: So next stop... Spider.
그래서...,
다음 목표는 스파이더
If we shut down his business,
그 놈의 사업을 폐쇄 시키면,
체포가 되겠지
maybe he'd be a rat.
We got a lawyer.
우린 변호사가 있었지..
We needed her to testify
that she bought coke from him.
그녀가 그 놈에게서
코카인을 구입 했다는 진술이 필요했다
She was a good lawyer.
그녀는 좋은 변호사였다
Me and my partner paid a visit
to Club 404 of Harlem.
나와 내 동료는
할렘가 404클럽을 심문하러 갔다
A word about him...
난 그 놈이 걱정되었다
Tom Cowen's been my partner
for almost 40 years.
톰 코완은 30년 동안
줄곧 내 동료였다
He's the best cop
I've ever seen.
내가 여태까지 겪어 본 경찰중에
그가 최고라고 생각한다
I'm always the one
following him through the door.
난 항상 문틈 사이로
그를 뒤따르지
There's a bullet
that was meant for me
그 놈 몸뚱아리를 쏜 총알은
나를 위한 것이었다
that's lodged in his torso.
He was my role model.
그는 내 마누라였다
The day I stopped
trying to be Tom Cowen
내가 "톰 코완 이기를 포기했던 그 날"이
내 인생에서 최고의 날이였다
was the greatest day
of my life.
증거
Hey, Rooster,
저기..
루스터
I was going through the files
on poetry boy.
시에 관한 사건 파일을 찾고 있는 중인데..
That's an interesting way
to pass your time.
당신이 모르고 지나친
흥미로운 것이 있던데..
Okay, there was a gun
찰스 렌달이 수감되어 있을 때,
총이 발견 되었죠
found on Charles Randall
when he was arrested.
Yeah.
그래?
Now in all the other shootings
the gun was left at the scene,
현장에서 발견한 총과는
다른 총이였죠
but there are a lot of similarities.
So I mentioned it to Perez and Riley.
그런데 유사한 점들이 너무 많아요
페레즈와 레일리 형사에게 그걸 언급했죠
누군가 그 죄수에게 심문하러 가야 하는데...
I think somebody should go
interview him in prison.
I think there may be a connection.
뭔가 연결 고리가 있을 거에요
That's a good idea,
but not Perez and Riley.
좋은 생각이네
허나, 페레즈와 레일리 형사는 안돼
I mean, not those guys.
They'll screw it up.
그들은 이 사건들을 망칠게 뻔해
This is too important.
이건 너무 중요해
Turk and I will handle Randall, okay?
터크와 내가 함 다뤄 볼께, 알겠나?
수고해
Good work.
Detectives, Charles Randall.
형사님들, "찰슨 렌달"요
What the fuck
do you two scumbags want?
너희 두 새끼가 원하는 게 뭐야?
What a greeting.
인사군...
You like poetry, Chuck?
시 좋아하나, 찰스?
What?
뭐?
Do you like poetry?
시를 좋아 하냐고?
Yeah.
Roses are red, violets are blue,
그래
장미들은 빨강, 제비꽃들은 파랑
I want to poke out your fucking eyes
with my dick, you fuck.
너의 눈을 내 자지로 찌르고 싶어,
개노무 새끼야
How's that?
- 어떻게?
- 시를 짓는 거라 생각했는데, 아니였군
I thought you'd rhyme.
You didn't.
Fuck you.
Fuck both of you.
엿 먹어, 둘다 엿 먹으라고...
날 여기서 꺼내쥬슈
Get me out of here.
Why the fuck did we even bother
going out there?
대체 왜 우리가 거기를 간 거야?
What would it look like
if we didn't go?
우리가 가지 않는다면,
우릴 의심할 게 아닌가?
Are you gonna relax?
긴장이 풀렸나?
Relax.
풀렸네
Yeah, I'll just take it out
on Karen later.
나중에 카렌에게 화풀이 할래
The more I'm with her,
the more abuse she wants.
가면 갈수록 우릴 옥죄이는군
Sounds like fun.
재미있겠어
Hey, you want to take her
off my hands?
자네가 나 대신 해줄래?
Be careful, partner, because I have
a very special effect on women.
조심하게, 동료
난 정말 여자에게 환장한 놈 이거든..
Go wild.
난폭하게 해
Whatever.
그런 짓 안하네
I can't believe I had to face
that piece of shit and look like an idiot.
사실, 내 모습이 역겨울 정도의
멍청한 놈으로 보여주고 싶지 않네
Eh, fuck him.
He's where he belongs.
그 놈을 죽여,
감옥에 있잖은가
I'm sorry, partner,
I'm really sorry.
그 놈에게는 미안해,
정말 미안해
Stop worrying about it.
그 이야기는 고만하게
Whatever happens,
I'm not taking you down with me.
무슨 일이 일어나도,
나 혼자 죽지 않을 걸세
Don't worry about me.
I'm all right, believe me.
난 걱정말게, 괜찮으니..
날 믿게나...
I don't know what I was thinking.
I just don't know what I was thinking.
웬지 모르겠네,
어떻게 생각해야 할지 모르겠어
You know what you was thinking?
You were thinking
뭘 생각할지 모른다고?
자넨 10살 난 여자 아이의..
두개골이 깨진 것을 생각하고 있잖은가
about a 10-year-old girl
who had her skull crushed.
Yeah, I tried to stop you,
but you know what?
그래, 난 자네를 저지할려고 했지만......
그날 자네에게 탐복 했네
I admired you that day,
what you did.
자네가 뭘 했든...
That was righteous.
.....그건 의로운 살인 이였네
And you don't second-guess yourself
on something like that.
그리고 다음 번에 또 그런 일이
일어난다고 해도, 자기 자신을 비판하지 말게
Okay, I'm the killer.
좋아, 내가 범인이라면..
I'm the killer.
I show up at your door
내가 살인자임을 보여줬고
문쪽을 향해 쐈어
or your car window,
또는 차 유리판에....
몇 가지 이유 때문에, 당신이 문을 열었어
and for some reason
you open your door,
you roll down
your car window for me.
당신이 차 유리판에 굴러 떨어졌어..
나 때문에..
So who am I?
그럼? 내가 누구지?
Someone I know.
제가 아는 사람이거나..
Maybe a nice set of tits.
멋진 가슴이겠죠..
And the poems?
What about the poems?
그 시는 어떤데?
You have to compose the poem
before you got there, right?
범인이 그곳에 있기 전에,
그 시를 작문해야죠, 그렇죠?
Otherwise what, you're gonna
blow out the guy's brains,
그렇지 않으면, 그 남자의 머리를 박살낸 후,
앉아서 "겨울연가"를 쓰겠죠?
sit down and write a little sonnet
for yourself?
그 시에는 지문이 없었네
No prints on the poems,
so probably
I wore gloves when I wrote it.
그래서 말야, 십중 팔구는
장갑을 끼고 썼을 거야
You obviously know your victims.
Between that and the easy access,
범인은 확실히 희생자를 알거나,
쉽게 넙나 들었을 거야
I guess that they know you too.
They must.
나 또한 희생자들이
범인을 알았을 거야
이 놈들은 모두 불한당이고,
어느 누구도 신뢰하지 않았죠
These guys are all scumbags.
They're not gonna trust anyone,
open the door for anyone,
especially if they don't know them.
아무에게 문을 열어 주지 않았고,
확실한 건, 그들을 몰랐던 거죠
Yeah, but I more than know them.
맞아, 맞아..
허나 범인은 그들을 더 잘 알지
I know everything about them.
I know their moves,
범인은 그들의 모든 것을 알어..
그들의 움직임, 패턴, 일정표까지 알아
their patterns,
I know their schedules.
Okay, so you're following them.
You're staking them out.
그래서 그들을 뒤따라 가면서,
제거를 한 거죠
Anyone gonna say it?
하고 싶은 말 없나?
What?
뭘?
Fuck me.
놀랍군
- He's right, it's a cop.
- No.
- 맞아요, 경찰
- 아니야
Let's slow down, fellows.
We're getting way ahead of ourselves.
우리 시야에 사라지기 전에
일이나 하세.......
- Come on, it's a cop, you know it.
- I don't know shit. Neither do you.
- 맞아요! 경찰, 맞다구요
- 경찰은 아냐, 그건 아니야
I'm telling your right now,
it's a cop, it's a cop, it's a cop.
분명히 말하는데, 경찰이에요
범인은 경찰, 경찰요
What do you mean,
"It's a cop, it's a cop, it's a cop"?
경찰은 절대 아냐, 경찰이야, 경찰
자넨 왜 "경찰이에요"라고 고집 피우나...
- Where do you come off saying it's a cop?
- Easy, partner, he's just saying it.
- 진정하게, 그냥 말로만 그러는 거네...
- 자넨 뭔 소리를 하는 거야?
- What are you talking about?
- He's just saying...
I know, I know, I know
what he's saying.
뭔 소리인지 나도 아네!
And I'm saying it's bullshit.
말같은 소리를 하란 말야!
Shoot me. What the fuck?
But don't say it's a cop.
그러거나 말거나...
허나 "경찰이에요"라고 말하지 말란 말야
♪ You cast a spell on me ♪
♪ I was blind and now I see ♪
♪ You work your magic,
that's the key ♪
♪ You wave your wand ♪
♪ And cast a spell on me... ♪
Turk: So what about dinner?
저녁 어때?
You feel like going out?
나가고 싶은데?
Where?
어디?
I don't care.
You're the one going.
어딜 가든, 상관 없어
What is your problem?
왜 그러는데?
No problem.
왜 그러다니?
If you feel like hanging around,
be my guest.
나랑 시간을 보내고 싶으면..
당신은 그저 손님이야
I don't feel like going out.
나 갈 마음이 쏵 사라졌어
Fine, just don't bug me.
좋아
날 내버려 둬, 지금은 내 시간이니..
그리고 당신 도움 따위는 필요 없어
This is the best part of my day
and I don't need you fucking it up.
So you only fuck cops?
그래서?
경찰들하고만 섹스를 하는군?
Once in a while
I do a fireman or an ex-con.
가끔은 말야,
소방관 그리고 범죄자
You lump us in together?
한 사람에게 만족을 못하는 군?
Well, I have some respect
for firemen.
난 차분한 소방관을 사랑해
Fuck you.
헛소리 하지마
You know why they take away
your nightstick
당신이 경찰 유니폼을 벗을 때,
왜 당신 곤봉을 뺏는 줄 알아?
- when you hang up your uniform?
- No.
몰라
They don't trust you with it.
그건 당신을 신뢰하지 않기 때문이야
Right now I wouldn't trust
myself with it either.
지금은 내 자신도 신뢰하지 않아
그래서 당신이 날 사랑하잖아
Shit, you'd probably love that.
Too bad you never met
Van Luytens.
존 반 루이텐스를 만나지 않은 게 아쉽군
둘 궁합이 환상적 일텐데..
You two really would have
hit it off great.
At least somebody finally
brought some justice down
그 놈의 결정적인 죽음은...
바로 자지가 작기 때문이지
on that dickless little fuck.
Now that is who I'd like to meet.
그게 바로 내가 원하는 만남이야
Well, maybe you'll get
your wish one day.
아마도 당신이 원하는 그 날이 오겠지
They think it's a cop.
그들은 범인이 경찰이래
- Makes sense.
- Bullshit.
- 일리가 있군
- 말도 안돼, 그건 사이코 같은 소리야
It's just some fucking psychopath.
Well, there's plenty of those
on the job.
오.....
근무 중에도 그런 것들이 많지
- Are you sleeping well?
- Not really.
잠은 잘 자나요?
- 아니요
- 네
- Yep.
- Eating well?
잘 먹고요?
- No.
- Yeah.
- 아니요
- 네
Any recurring nightmares?
- 악몽에 시달리나요?
- 네, 영원히 당신과 처박히고 싶소
Yeah, that I'm stuck
in a room with you forever.
Nope.
아니요
Do you think you're fit
to return to duty?
임무에 돌아 가는게,
지금이 적기라고 보시나요?
- Abso-fucking-lutely.
- Yeah.
- 당근이죠
- 네
- You ever think about retiring?
- You mean, death with benefits?
- 퇴직은 생각해 보셨나요?
- 당신 의미는...
사망 보험금?
What's not to like?
또는 그와 비슷한?
- You ever think about retiring?
- Not really.
퇴직에 대해 한번이라도 생각은
하셨나요?
아니 올시다
What have I got to look forward to?
장래에 내가 뭘 할거라 보시오?
내 26번 배로 항만을 항해?
Sailing my 26-footer
around Sheepshead Bay,
umpiring cops' softball?
경찰 소프트볼의 심판?
- How about corporate security work?
- It's too dangerous.
경비원 일은 어때요?
- So what are you gonna do?
- Maybe I'll buy a boat.
- 너무 위험해
- 그럼 무슨 일 하실려고?
보트를 사겠죠
Turk: All right, look,
I don't know if I believe this,
좋아, 내가 믿으면 어쩔수 없지만,
자네들이 말한 것에 제안하고 싶네...
Turk: All right, look,
I don't know if I believe this,
but I'm just gonna
throw it out there.
You guys say we're looking
for one of our own,
우리들의 합의점을 도출해 보세
but what if it was an ex-cop,
somebody with an axe to grind?
만약 경찰을 사칭하는 자면?
누군가 경찰 유니폼을 입었겠지
You got one in mind?
선배는 하나만 생각하는 군요?
He's thinking about Martin Baum
내 동료는 "마틴 바움"을 생각하겠지
our old lieutenant.
오래된 경찰
So what's the story with him?
그 용의자를 어떻게 하실려고요?
He got fired a few years ago.
몇년 전에 경찰 일 그만두고,
I'm not saying there's any motive,
but he knew all the victims.
동기가 있을 거란 말은 하지 않겠지만,
그는 모든 희생자를 알지
Yeah, but Turk,
I knew most of those guys.
그럼 터크,
나도 희생자들을 아네
So did you, Riley, Perez.
Even Karen knew 'em.
그리고 자네, 레일리, 페레즈,
심지어 코렐리까지..
- I'm just throwing it out there.
- Well, maybe you killed 'em.
난 그냥 제안을 했을 뿐이네
아마 자네가 그들을 죽였겠지
Yeah, maybe I did.
맞아, 내가 그랬네
The poems and the placement
of the weapons
시들, 그리고 무기의 위치
우리가 아는 살인들에 연관성이 있네
are all we've got
linking the kills,
which means what we gotta do now
is get humping on the forensics.
우리가 조사 할려는 것은
바로 법의학에 희망을 걸려는 거지
That shouldn't be
too much of a problem.
선배 시를 함 해결해 보죠,
우린 선배 여자친구를 먹었죠
We already got the girl
working on that.
That's right, Karen's been
humping on it all week, as we speak.
맞아, 왕방울, 긴 한 주였지
죽여줬지
What did you say?
뭐라고?
Here we go again.
다시 함 가보세..
- You should watch your mouth.
- Oh, yeah?
자네 입 조심하게
조심하지 않아도 돼요, 카렌과 사이몬은
그냥 지나간 일이니, 걱정하지는 마세요
He didn't mean anything by it.
Karen and him are ancient history.
- College boy can't speak for himself?
- Yeah, I can speak for myself.
그럼, 페레즈가 자기 자신에 대해 말하던가?
네, 전 제 자신에 대해 말해요
제 자신에 대해 말할께요, 엿 드세요 터크!
Let me speak for myself...
fuck you, Turk.
Mutt, I'm gonna hit you
on the head with this barbell.
그럼, 네놈에게 총알을 박아 주겠어...
I'm not better than you.
You're not better than me, man.
- 총알 보다는 다른 걸 해주시죠..
- 자네, 호주머니에 총알을 넣게
You put your balls
in your pocket.
And you, fellow officers,
그리고 자넨, 경관들을 따라가고..
a little courtesy
for a fellow professional, you know?
자넨, 선배에게 용서를 구하고..
Please. Are we gonna move on
here now?
어서!
이곳에 나가야 하지 않겠어?
What are we doing?
Where were we?
나가세, 안 갈 텐가?
Talking about Martin Baum.
What's his story?
- "마틴 바움"에 다시 이야기 하죠
- 내용이 뭐죠?
Some guys under him
got caught taking money.
내가 아는 몇명이 돈을 가져갔지
바움은 그들을 모른체 했고, 은폐 하려고 시도했지
Baum stood up for them,
tried to cover it up.
He do time?
형기를 치렀나요?
Well, they pressed charges,
but he plead out and resigned.
그들은 그에게 죄를 덮어씌웠고,
그는 항변했고 결국 사임했지
So what's his beef with you?
그럼 문제가 뭐였어요?
난 그를 보호하기 위해
거짓말을 할려고 했지만, 그렇지 않았지
I could have lied to protect him,
but I didn't.
Okay, but if he's got a beef with you,
why not go after you?
문제가 있었다고 치죠,
그가 선배를 왜 잡지않죠? 왜 죽이지도 않고?
Why not kill you? Why go around
acting like a serial killer,
왜 연쇄 살인범 처럼 쫓기죠?
말이 안돼요
killing all these degenerates?
It doesn't make any sense.
- I'm just telling you.
- I'm telling you it doesn't make sense.
- 난들 아나, 난 그냥 이야기 할 뿐이네
- 저도 이야기 할 뿐이죠, 말이 전혀 안돼요
I'm throwing it out there.
I'm saying this is what it is.
난 제안을 하는 것 뿐일세
You want to check him out or not?
I don't give a shit.
- 자네가 조사하고 싶나? 뭐라하지 않겠네
- 말이 전혀 안돼요
- It doesn't make any sense.
- You're the ones that think it's a cop.
자넨 그가 경찰이라고 생각하잖아
난 그가 "경찰에게 불만을 갖는다"라고 말한 것 뿐..
I'm just saying here's a cop
with a chip on his shoulder.
Check him out if you want.
I don't give a shit.
자네가 원하면 확인해 봐......
일단 진정하고, 왜 바움이 용의자가
되어야 했는지 이유를....네?
Calm down and give a better reason
why Baum could be a suspect, okay?
PMS, gotta be.
월경 전 증후군이야..
- Hey, guys.
- What's going on?
어서 와요
무슨 일 인데?
I came over to bring you
the FBI report
FBI에게 당신의 보고서 작성차
여기에 왔어요
on the paper
and handwriting.
You don't have a problem
with me looking over the evidence
제가 주위를 둘러 봐도,
괜찮죠?
that I collected and processed
for you, do you?
당신 사건에 수집과 처리
- No problem.
- Put it back, Karen.
문제 없어
- This is fascinating.
- Let's go, come on.
- 제 자리에 갖다 놔
- 그게, 이거 흥미로운데..
Come on, let's go, let's go.
어서, 어서.....
일어나, 일어나, 어서...일어나
- What?
- Come on, let's go.
Get your hands off me.
이봐요, 손 치워요
I'll give you a little privacy.
I don't want to interrupt anything here.
난 자네에게 약간의 사생활을 주고 싶네
자네를 방해하고 싶진 않아
Are you afraid of me
looking at your old case files?
당신들 제가 이 파일들을 보는 게
두렵나요? 그래요?
- Is that it?
- Okay, I'm gone. Enjoy.
좋아, 난 가겠네
즐겁게 해
- What?
- What is it with you?
당신 대체 왜 그러는데?
당신 대체 왜 그러냐고!
- What is it with you?
I'm sorry about last night, okay?
지난 밤에는 미안해요, 됐죠?
I really am. It's a habit.
전 정말이지..버릇이 되서...
버릇은 고칠 수 있죠? 맞죠?
Habits can be broken, right?
That's bullshit.
- 그건 거짓말 이야
- 아니에요
No.
I'm totally serious, all right?
저 정말로 진지해요, 네?
It's not bullshit,
거짓말이 아니에요
really.
정말로..
Perez: Why do you think
Turk was so quick to take the lead
자넨 터크 선배가 이번 연쇄 살인범을
조사하는데 멋지게 이끌수 있다고 생각하나?
on the poetry case, huh?
To keep us from finding the killer, man.
우리가 살인범을 찾는데 방해하고,
내가 행방을 감춘다면, 나도 그렇게 되겠지
That's what I would do
if I was covering my tracks.
He sticks us on this Baum stakeout
'cause it's more misdirection.
터크 선배가 우릴 부당한 지시를 하면,
우리도 바움처럼 되겠지
Makes sense.
말이 되는군
I hate that Turk, man.
난 터크 선배가 싫어
Hey, he's coming out.
He's coming out.
이봐, 이쪽으로 와, 온다.....
Oh, at 2:45 in the morning.
새벽 2:45분 이군
Is it killing time
or is he just killing time?
살인 할 시간인가?
살인 할 시간은 아닌데.....
Come on, Baum,
go kill someone already.
어서, 바움 누군가를 죽여줘........
Perez: Yeah, kill Turk, man.
He's the one setting you up.
맞아, 터크 선배를 죽여, 자넬 모함했으니..
우리 부탁을 들어줘...
Do us all a favor.
Hey, did you see Turk's
marksmanship scores?
자네 터크 선배가 그 동안
세운 기록을 보았나?
Did you see this?
It's ridiculous.
터무니없는 기록이지
99개의 서브, 100의 70야드
Service... 99,
70 out of 100.
Combat Association awards,
department commendations.
해설 부분에서 전투 협회의 상
This guy could take out your left nut
at 50 yards.
이 선배는 자네 목숨을
50야드는 더 뺏을 수 있네
Perez: Did you see the computer
trajectories, man?
컴퓨터를 조회 해 본 결과,
자기 신변이 철저했어
Not one stray slug.
Even Berkowitz put a couple
in the Corinthian leather.
Riley: What about Karen?
She come up with anything new?
- 코렐리는 어때, 뭐 새로운 거라도?
- 아니, 아직은 없어
Perez: No, not yet.
If Baum kills somebody
I don't want us to be in the car
바움이 누군가 죽이면,
사건이 일어 날 때까지 기다리지 않겠네, 알겠나?
waiting when it happens, okay?
I'll go.
내가 가지
Attaboy, Teddy, attaboy.
좋아, 테디, 좋아...
자네가 자랑스러워
I'm proud of you, son.
You're Perez, right?
자네가 "페레즈" 맞나?
Yeah.
네
I'm Martin Baum.
난 "마틴 바움"일세
I got a permit for this.
난 총기 허가증이 있지
I work security
in the diamond district.
난 디머 지역의 치안을 위해 일했지
So you figure it's a cop
doing the poetry killings?
그래, 자네들이 추정하는 인물이
경찰이라 이건가?
Someone says, "Check out Baum.
He thinks he got a raw deal."
그래서, "바움을 조사하고",
"그가 살인을 했다고 생각해" 이건가?
That's what passes
for police work these days?
그래서, 터크가 말한
요약이 이거 아닌가?
Do you think
you got a raw deal?
- 터크 선배가 잘못된 생각을...?
- 잘못 짚었지
Damn straight.
- Life sucks.
- Yeah.
- 인생은 엿 같죠
- 맞아
- Everything okay, Simon?
- Teddy, where the fuck were you, man?
- 괜찮나? 사이몬?
- 테드, 도대체 어딜 간겨?
Anything else you want to tell us,
Lieutenant Baum?
- 어떻게 지내슈?
- 저희에게 말하고 싶은 게 있나요, 바움 반장님?
- I got something for you in my pocket.
- Huh-uh!
내 주머니에 있는 것을
자네에게 주고 싶네
A passport, credit card receipts,
boarding passes.
여권, 신용 카드 영수증들,
탑승권들.....
The day Brady was killed
그가 죽은 날에,
난 브라질 고객에게 경호를 했었네
I was escorting a client
to Brazil.
Man: Judgment is
the dominion of the Lord.
And if this person,
this worthless rapist
or murderer,
as you describe him,
"만약 그가 진실로 회개하는..
진정으로 늬우친다면.."
if he is truly repentant
and seeks absolution,
it must be granted to him.
"그의 죄를 사하여 주시옵소서"
Your name doesn't ring a bell,
"이름이 생각나지 않지만.."
but I've had so many
altar boys over the years.
"전 지난 수 십년 동안
수 많은 사제들이 있었죠"
Turk's voice: So many altar boys
수 많은 사제 소년들은
자기들 이름을 거론하긴 어렵지
that it's hard to remember
their names.
My name is David Fisk,
Detective First Grade.
내 이름은 데이비드 피쉬 형사
You may not
remember me now,
내 이름을 기억할 진 몰라도,
"자네 남은 일생동안 내 이름을 기억할 거라" 장담하지
but I guarantee you'll remember my name
for the rest of your life.
Father Connell,
may he rot in hell.
코넬 신부, 그는 지옥에 떨어질 거다
14 down, one to go.
13명을 죽이고, 나머지 하나
Karen: White underwear
below the knee.
하얀 속옷, 무릎까지는 파랑
- Briefs-style.
같은 형태로, 약품 처리반은 어디?
Large tweezers.
I am removing a card that has been
inserted in the rectum of the deceased
고인의 엉덩이속에 끼워 넣은
카드를 제거하고....
and placing it
in a plastic evidence bag.
그리고 나서
플라스틱 증거물 가방에 보관하고...
- I'll be right back.
- All right.
- 다시 올께
- 알겠어요
Hey. It's another one,
어서와요
또 다른 사건이에요
handwritten.
"The old man
who the children trust,
어린이들이 신뢰한 이 늙은 남자는
정욕을 참지 못하였다
Unable to control his lust,
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
재는 재로, 먼지는 먼지로
The church can't stop him.
Someone must."
척은 그를 멈출수 밖에 없었다
누군가는 해야만 한다
I'll see what else I can find.
그 밖에 뭐 새로운 게 있나 볼께요
What's the matter with you?
나의 정의는 뭐지?
Father Connell gave me
my first communion
코넬 신부님은 베네룩스에서 돌아 왔을때..
나에게 첫 성찬식을 해 주셨지
back in Bensonhurst.
Hey, guys.
Sorry we didn't get a chance to call.
- 자네들에게 연락하지 않아서 미안하네
- 알아요, 전 선배 때문에 온 거에요
- Yeah, I bet you are.
- Go over there, take a look around.
저쪽에 가 보게, 주위를 둘러보고 조사하게,
우리 나중에 기록을 비교하겠네, 알았나?
We'll compare notes later, okay?
Looks like our friend just settled
an old score with the priest,
목사에게 묵은 원한을 풀었던
친구가 죽인 것 같아
left him with his pants down.
- 목사 팬티가 내려졌네
- 오, 제발..
- Come on.
- No, look.
- 한번 봐
- 제발, 그런식으로 이야기 하지 마세요
Come on, don't talk like that.
- Hey, look for yourself.
- Have a little respect.
이봐, 구석구석 잘 살펴보게
Next thing they're gonna tell us
Lieutenant Baum was an altar boy here.
잘 들어봐, 터크 선배는 "바움"이 이곳에서
사제 소년으로 지냈다고 말 할걸세
Tell me about it.
These two guys fucking stink.
정말 못 믿겠어,
이 두 선배는 악취를 너무 풍겨
Look, Doctor,
you read the poems.
봐요, 의사선생, 시를 쓸 줄 알면,
가능하겠죠?... 그게 경찰일수도 있겠죠
It is possible, right,
that this guy is a cop?
I've never seen it.
아니, 본 적이 없네
경찰이 연쇄 살인범이란 소리를 들어본 적이 없네
I've never even heard
about a cop serial killer.
Come on, girls,
let's go, let's go.
힘내 얘들아!
어서 끝내! 힘내!
Yeah. Go go go go go
go go go go!
달려, 달려, 달려...
Safe.
Doc, give us a tip.
How are we gonna catch this guy?
의사선생., 저희에게 제보 좀 주쇼
이놈을 어떻게 잡을수 있죠?
You don't have to worry
about that.
그건 걱정하지 말게
그는 잡히길 원할 거야
He wants to get caught.
You don't have any better place
to have lunch?
점심을 위한 더 좋은 장소라도 원하오?
I wanted to thank you.
- 고맙다는 말을 하고 싶어요
- 스파이더에 대해서?
What, about Spider?
Yeah.
네, 병원에서 절 볼봐 주시고,
절 격려해 줘서요
And for looking in on me
at the hospital
and the encouragement.
Why would he want that?
- 그가 왜 잡히길 원하죠?
- 잠시 후면, 성이 차지 않아서 도망칠 걸세
After a while
getting away with it isn't enough.
Jessica: So is your daughter
on the team?
당신 딸이 저 팀에 있나요?
No, she used to play,
but now she's 25, living in California,
아니, 전에는 야구를 했었지만,
지금은 25살이고 캘리포니아에 산다우
five years sober
and working as a nurse.
- 간호사로 일하지
- 그럼 부인은요?
And her mother?
Her mother died
when she was very young.
딸이 어렸을 때,
아내가 죽었소
Doctor: He wants everybody to know
that he got away with it,
범인은 무사히 빠져나간 것을
모두가 알기를 바랄 걸세
to show everybody
just how brilliant he is.
자기가 얼마나 멋진 놈인지
모두에게 보여주려 할 걸세
Most of these killings were criminals
in Rooster's and his beat, right?
이번 살인들이 대부분 바로 수탉앞에서
그리고 범인의 얼굴 때문에 무죄가 됐죠, 맞죠?
And then he all but threatens
to kill Van Luytens
그리고 범인은 수많은 목격자들 앞에서
줄행랑을 치기 위해 죽이고 협박했죠
in front of hundreds of witnesses.
And then he sends us
그리고 나서 범인은 "바움" 반장님을
모함하고 추격하게 만드는 거죠
on this crazy wild goose chase
after Lieutenant Baum, didn't he?
- 맞지? 그가 그랬지?
- 맞아, 그랬어
- Yes, he did.
- Why would he do that? Why?
- 왜? 왜죠?...
- 자네, 자네 말야...
You gotta show me more than that.
So far you got shit.
자네가 엉뚱한 만큼
확실한 정보를 더 보여주게...
- Give him more, man.
- You want more?
- 반장님에게 보여주게
- 더 보여줘요? 교회 기록은 어때요?
- How about the church records?
- The very ones that Turk was
터크 선배가 그곳에서
열심히 종사한 기록들 입니다
so diligently pursuing.
How about that?
It turns out our most recent victim,
the late Father Connell,
지금 드러난 건,
가장 최근에 희생된 코넬 신부님은..
was moved all over the place...
eight parishes in 20 years.
...20년 동안 8교구를 옮겨 다니셨죠
카톨릭 사제처럼 왜 옮겨 다니셨죠?
Why would they do that
with a Catholic priest? It's obvious.
확실한 건, 신부님은 사제 뒤에서
어린얘들에게 성찬식을 하셨죠
He's giving the children
more than communion behind the altar.
Now Turk already admits
to knowing this guy as a child.
터크 선배가 어렸을 때니 이미 알고 있었죠
정말 타당성이 있죠
It's very plausible.
Lieutenant: This priest,
this Father Connell,
성직자인 코넬 신부께서
자네의 첫 성찬식을 했나?
he gave you your first
holy communion, eh?
He did.
- 그 분이 하셨죠
- 그 분이 불법을 저질를 만한 일을 하셨나?
Did he every try to do
anything inappropriate? I mean...
I know what you mean.
No, never.
- 내 말은...
- 무슨 말인지 알아요, 아니요 절대...
Okay, fine.
Is there any reason
좋아, 그러면..그 분이 부정을 했다고
다른 사람들이 그런 생각을 하는 거지?
why somebody out there
might think that he did?
No.
네, 제가 용의자 인가요?
반장님?
Am I a suspect here, Lieutenant?
No,
아닐세, 동료들이 냄새를 맡기 시작했네.......
but these bodies
are starting to smell.
A lot of it is drifting
in your direction.
그 냄새가 자네를 향하고 있네
Drifting or being pushed?
- 대세? 떠밀리고 있는건 가요?
- 내가 무슨 말을 하겠나?
What can I say?
You got connections
to most of these victims.
자넨 최근의 희생자와 연락이 있었네
자넨 테레사 수녀님이 아닐세
You're not exactly
Mother Teresa.
I never had any problem
with that priest.
- 전 그분하고 문제가 전혀 없었어요
- 알겠네, 좋아..
Okay. Okay, fine.
That settles it.
해결해 봄세
I had a talk with Riley and Perez.
- "레일리" 그리고 "페레즈"와 의논했네
- 좋은 경찰이죠
Good cops.
Don't fuck around, okay?
Just listen.
- 잡소리 집어 치워, 알겠나? 그냥 듣기만 해
- 듣고 있습니다
I'm listening.
They think
Turk might be our guy.
그들은 터크를 용의자로 보고있네
Oh, man. I gotta tell you,
오 이런, 제가 앉은 곳이
정말 재미있다고 말은 하고 싶네요
from where I'm sitting
that is so fucking funny.
You can't take that seriously.
그게 말이 된다고 보시나요? 네?
Everybody has pretty much
accepted the fact
우리들 중 한 명을 사냥한다는
사실은 거의 대부분 인정했네
- that we're chasing one of our own.
- But it ain't Turk.
허나 터크는 아닙니다
물론 이곳에 앉아 있는 저도 아니고요
Sure as I'm sitting here
he ain't the guy.
- You know that?
- Yes, I do.
- 자네 확실한가?
- 물론이죠
- How do you know that?
- Because I know it.
- 자네가 그걸 어떻게 아는데?
- 제가 확실히 알기 때문이죠
I know it to a moral certainty.
저도 틀림없다고 생각해요, 됐나요?
Okay?
This priest,
성직자인 코넬 신부님은
그가 어렸을때, 그의 주임 사제였네
this Father Connell...
he was Turk's priest
when he was a kid.
He told you that.
- 그가 반장님에게 말했잖아요
- 허나, "어린이 성추행범" 이라고 말 하지는 않았네
He didn't tell me this priest
was a child molester.
- I can't believe this bullshit.
- Believe it, all right?
- 전 믿을 수 없습니다
- 믿게나
- Turk's a good guy.
- You understand?
터크는 공정한 사람입니다
경찰 중에 최고죠
- He's the best cop you got.
- Don't you tell me what I gotta do.
나한테 이래라저래라 말아!
Don't you say a goddamn word
to him about this either,
그에게 어떠한 충고라도 하지 말게나
그렇지 않으면 자넨 끝장일 테니 말이야
or you're finished.
Can I speak now?
- 지금 말해도 돼죠?
- 하시게나....
Feel free.
He cares.
You know what I'm saying?
그가 걱정을 해요
제 말 뜻이 뭔지 아시겠죠?
Turk cares about people.
터크는 사람들을 걱정해요
I know he runs around
like a pit bull on crack sometimes.
그가 한번 경멸할 만한 짓을 했다고 해도,
문제 될게 전혀 없습니다
It doesn't matter.
He cares about protecting people.
그는 사람들을 보호하는데 만 걱정을 해요
And if you don't back him,
만약 반장님이 그를 믿지 않으시면,
후회 하실 겁니다
you will regret it.
Jesus.
- 오, 깜작이야!
- 미안
Sorry.
I just never rattled
anyone's cage before.
전에는 누굴 놀래케 하는 일은 하지 않았는데..
시간 있나?
- Got a minute?
- Yeah, what's up?
네, 무슨 일로?
You know me and Turk
are buddies, right?
터크와 내가 친구란 걸 알지?
Of course.
- 물론 이죠
- 그를 위해 뭐든지 할거네
I'd do anything for him.
He would do anything for you.
그도 당신을 위해 뭐든지 하겠죠....
Would you?
Would I what?
- 자네도 할 건가?
- 하다니 뭘요?
Would you do anything for him?
자네도 그를 위해 뭐든지 할 건가?
I don't know...
where is this going?
아니요,..., 그게.....,
어디로 가야할 지?
He wants you
to have sex with me.
- 그는 나랑 섹스 하기를 원하네
- 정말요?
Really?
He wouldn't mind.
신경쓰지 말게
그것 때문에 온게 아니니....
But that's not why I'm here.
Okay, why are you here?
좋아요, 왜 왔는데요?
Where were you
the night Rambo was killed
람보가 죽던 밤에,
자네는 어디에 있었나?
and Trager?
Got an alibi for those nights?
트래거 사건도 그렇고,
그날 밤에 알리바이라도 증명할 수 있나?
I mean, did you know either one
those guys before they were murdered?
그들이 죽기 전에, 이 희생자들을
알고 있었나 이 말일세
Makes you uncomfortable
when I talk like that.
- 알겠어요
- 이 질문으로 자네는 물론 불편하겠지
You look like you're guilty.
You're not guilty.
자네가 유죄가 아니더라도,
유죄처럼 보일 걸세
I know that.
You didn't kill those guys, did you?
자네가 그들을 죽이지 않았단 걸,
나도 아네, 안 그런가?
Now you know what Turk feels.
지금은 자네도
터크 입장을 알 걸세
I need you to get me
some information
자네에게 정보가 좀 필요하네.......신중히
discreetly.
Can you do that for me?
그래 줄 수 있는가?
You got it.
- 알겠어요, 그렇고말고요
- 이 살인범을 잡자고....
Absolutely.
Let's solve these fucking murders.
Oh.
- Rooster: Hey, boy genius.
- Perfect timing, buddy.
- 이봐, 똑똑한 친구
- 참 완벽한 시간이네요, 선배
Listen, you really worked
on Hingis, didn't you?
듣게, 자네 정말로 반장님에게 보고했나?
반장님이 내 동료를 의심하는데 말야
He was all worked up
about my partner.
Good. He should be.
네, 의심할 걸요
I think we should sit down,
see if we can square things, okay?
우리가 이 사건을 공평하게 처리 할수
있는지 사태를 지켜보자고, 알겠나?
All right. Want to meet at Montrose
at 8:00 PM?
- 알겠어요, 8시에 트레일러 술집에서 만나죠
- 9시로 하면 안되겠나?
Could you make that 9:00?
I gotta meet an old friend.
- 오랜 친구를 만나야 하네
- 네, 그렇게 하세요
Yeah, sure, whatever you want.
♪ Baby's got issues ♪
♪ Baby's got pains... ♪
- Hey, fellows.
- Hey.
안녕, 친구들
Thanks for coming.
와 줘서 고맙네
- This here is Cheryl Brooks.
- Hello, Cheryl Brooks.
- 이 여성은 "셜 브룩스"
- 안녕하세요 "셜 브룩스"
Cheryl's got something to tell you.
셜이 자네들에게 할 말이 있을 걸세
My daughter Lynn
제 딸, 린은 4년 전에 죽었죠
died four years ago.
She was 10 years old.
She was raped and she was murdered.
그 여자애는 10살 이였고,
강간과 살인을 당했지
The guy I was living with,
Charles...
찰스라는 놈팽이와
저는 같이 살고 있었죠
Charles Randall.
- 찰스 렌달
- 네, 찰스 렌달, 그 놈이 범인이였죠
Yeah, Charles Randall... he did it.
Why are you telling us this?
- 왜 저희에게 이런 이야기를 하시는지?
- 그 놈은 형벌을 모면 했으니깐....
Because he got off for that.
He was acquitted at trial.
그 놈 무죄로 풀려놨지
- Because?
- 이유가...?
- 이유는...
I testified for him.
- 제가 그를 위해 증언을 했어요
- 하다니 뭘요?
- You did what?
- I said he was with me.
저랑 같이 있었다고 증언을 했어요
You see, Cheryl here is
a very forgiving person,
알다시피, 셜은 사람을 쉽게 용서하지....
융통성이 없었지..
unlike us hard-asses.
- He threatened to kill me.
- Okay, Cheryl.
- 저를 죽인다고 협박했어요
- 그만, 셜, 됐네
Now you say goodbye
to the nice officers
멋진 형사분들께 "작별 인사" 해야죠
and you go on back home.
자 여기, 집에 가시면,
자기 자신을 술로 지새우지 마세요
Don't drink yourself to death.
Okay, so...
좋아,..., 그러면...
eh?
I want to hear you say it.
무슨 말을 하고 싶은지 듣고 싶네요
어서, 말해 보세요
Come on, say it.
We planted the gun
in Randall's apartment, okay?
우린 렌달 아파트에
총을 숨겨놨네, 알겠나?
I said it. Happy?
- 자 말했네, 기쁜가?
- 고마워요
- Thank you.
- Yes, I am.
- 네, 전 기뻐요
- 그런 상황이 오더라도 난 다시 하겠네
I'd do it again if I had to
'cause that fucking maggot
그 비열한 새끼는 영원히 도망 갈테니...
난 켕길 거 없네
could rot away for all eternity.
I'd sleep just fine.
So what do you want from us?
그럼 저희에게 원하는 게 뭐에요?
You guys think
my partner's a serial killer.
좋아, 자네들 생각은 내 동료가
이번 연속 살인범이라고 생각하지
You're way off.
자네들 잘못 짚었네
터크가 이 일을 했다고 보나?
You like Turk for this thing?
Go have your fun.
I'll go along with you.
자네들과 함께 할 걸세,
물론 도와 줄 걸세
I'll even help you.
But do not drag up Chuck Randall
and that fucking gun,
허나 그 빌어먹을 총으로
찰스 렌달을 죽이지 않았지
because if he walks out of jail
he's gonna end up dead.
그 놈이 감옥에서 걸어 나왔다면,
바로 죽음의 열차를 타겠지
Excuse me?
뭐라고요?
I'll put two
through his fucking head
연장으로 그 놈의 머리통을 쑤셔 넣겠다고...
myself.
...내가 직접 말일세
Done deal.
완벽하게.....
My grandmother loved opera.
제 할머니께서는 오페라를 좋아했고,
바느질로 우릴 키우셨죠
She supported us by sewing.
I used to thread needles
for my grandmother.
저도 바느짓을 하곤 했죠...
할머니를 위해서
- Gave all her money to church.
- You admired her?
교회에 모든 돈을 헌신 하셨죠
- 그녀를 동경 하셨나요?
- 숭배했죠
I worshipped her.
Rooster? Yeah, he's religious,
goes to church.
루스터? 신앙심이 있어서,
교회에 가곤 하죠
Prosky: How about you?
당신은요?
Turk's voice: Our job is keeping
99% of the population safe
저희는 1%의 나쁜 놈들로 부터
99% 시민들을 보호하는 일을 하죠
from the other 1%.
The problem is that we have to
spend half our lives with that 1%.
저희 인생의 반을 그 1% 놈들과
보내야 하는게 문제일 지라도,
And the better we do that job,
99% 시민들이 우리를 필요로 하는 한,
저희 임무를 완수 할겁니다
the less the other 99% think
they need us.
They're clueless.
그 놈들은 무지하죠
The only ones paying attention
on the street
거리에는 경찰들과 범죄자들 뿐이니,
주의를 잘 살펴봐야 합니다
are the cops and the criminals.
Everyone else is just
모든 사람들이 어디를 간다거나....,
쇼핑을 하더라도 말이죠...
going somewhere
or shopping.
- Umpire: Out.
- Come on.
I got an order here placing you
on restricted duty.
좀 더 엄격한 규율로,
자네에 대한 명령 일세
Now in plain English that means
you'll work at your desk.
사무직으로 일을 할 걸세
정신과 의사와 상담해도 좋을 거네
You might want to cooperate
with the shrink
next time you two meet,
and you will meet again.
다음에 만나고 싶으면,
자네 둘은 다시 파트너가 될 걸세
Cool my fucking heels.
Cool my fucking heels, huh?
누가 수습했어...,
어떤 새끼가 무마 했냐고!!!
I'm gonna blow a fucking hole
in that motherfucker Perez
페레즈 이 쌍노무 새끼, 아가리를
찢어 버려도 시원치 않을 버러지 같은 새끼
and blow right through his head
for putting me through this bullshit.
- Turk.
- Fuck, I'm gonna...
젠장! 그 개새끼를 죽여 버릴 거야
kill that motherfucker.
Calm down. What the hell is it?
You're making all the wrong moves.
진정하게, 이런다고 뭐가 달라지는데?
자넨 잘못된 수를 둔 거네
What are you talking about?
This ain't a chess game, partner.
자네 뭔 소리를 하는 건가?
이건 체스 게임이 아닐세, 파트너!
Who knows? Maybe it is.
You go at Perez now...
혹시 아나, 그거 일지도 모르지..
가봤자 득될 게 없네, 누가 기쁠 것 같나?
자네만 그 놈의 함정에 걸리는 꼴 일세
you know what's gonna happen?
You're gonna walk right into a trap.
You are.
They're just waiting for you.
자네만!
자네가 걸리기를 기다리겠지
Fucking Hingis.
빌어먹을 반장님도 너무 하는군,
그 놈을 믿다니......
Fucking Hingis believes him.
He actually fucking believes
that motherfucking Perez.
반장님이 페레즈,
그 개노무 새끼의 말을 믿다니
Stay back. Wait.
진정해, 잠시만...
적당한 때를 기다리게...,
Wait for the right time,
then fire away.
...그리고 나서 질러 버려
지금은 아닐세, 지금은 적당한 때가 아닐세
Not now. Now is not the right time.
Believe me.
날 믿게
You believe me?
Now is not the time.
자네 날 믿지?
지금은 적당한 때가 아니야
Uh-huh.
- Please.
- Yeah.
Hey, Turk, I gotta skip tonight.
My class ran late.
저기, 터크, 오늘밤은 건너 뛰어야 겠어
수업이 늦게 끝나
But I'll see you
tomorrow, all right?
내일 보자, 알았지?
어제 반장님과의 일어난
일은 정말 안됐어
And I'm sorry about what happened
with you and Lieutenant Hingis today.
It's gonna be fine.
It'll blow over.
괜찮을 거야, 가라앉을 테니...
그러게 말이야..사람들은 과민방응 하잖아
People are just... everyone's crazy.
People are overreacting.
All right? Good night.
알았지? 잘 있어
It's a cop, it's a cop, it's a cop.
"경찰이 범인, 경찰이야, 경찰이야..."
What you got for me, good-looking?
뭘 준비했지, 이쁘니?
Mark my words, there's a reason
Perez is gunning for me.
내 말 좀 듣게, 페레즈가 날 조사한
이유가 분명히 있을 거야
- Perez is too smart to be that stupid.
페레즈는 멍청할 정도로 똑똑하네
For one thing, all that college-boy crap...
that's bullshit.
대학교를 딱 1년만 다녔네,
그게 말이 된다고 보나?
He did one year at SUNY,
only one year.
- 1년 다녔네, 그것 뿐이야, 딱 1년
- 알겠네
No kidding.
They threw him out...
disruptive influence.
그들이 그 놈을 그만두게 하고,
그 놈의 설득력을 누그러 뜨렸지
And I hear from the 240 he mixed it up bad
with a captain over there.
2미터 40cm인 다벳과 캡틴 래리에게 들었는데,
이 새끼는 정말 개노무 새끼라고 말하더라
The guy is a total
fucking asshole.
BMW 4 series,
BMW 3번째 시리즈, 메르세데스벤츠 CLK, 박살났지
(자동차 경주 게임에 대한 이야기)
Mercedes CLK... too light.
BMW 7 series...
the biggest engine.
BMW 7번째 시리즈, 큰 엔진으로
안 보이게 하고 시작했지
That's what you have to get.
If they shoot at you,
그들이 날 겨냥했으면,
자네들도 그곳에서 벗어났을 걸세.....
you still want
to get the fuck out of there...
Bentley... very good
벤틀리 차 정말 죽이지, 왜냐하면...
because can fuck two prostitutes
in back seat
...뒷 자석에서 2명의 창녀들과
빠구리를 할 수 있지
and mount flame-thrower
on the hood. Da?
그리고 후드에 화염 방사기로 달수 있지
안 그래?
Da.
맞아
- Man: What about a Cadillac?
- Russian: Come on,
the fucking car can't turn
fucking corner. Are you kidding me?
젠장..., 모퉁이에서......
자네 지금 날 놀리나?
You know either one of those
Neanderthals?
자네 혹시 네안테르탈인들을 아는가?
The wop is Joe Scianci from Bensonhurst.
He's a mid-level guy.
물론, 판시나 지역에서 "Johcey Ancey"를
쳐 부셨지...감비노 처럼
What about lvan?
그럼 이반은 어때?
러시안인 Yevgeny Mugalat
(비디오 게임 말하는 사람 이름),
Russian guy,
Yevgeny Magulat,
an enforcer for the Italians,
works with Gambinos a lot.
가이아나인에게 엄격히 대했고,
근면한 감비노에겐 잘했지
That shit's getting to me.
- 그녀가 나를 수사하네
- 나도 아네
I know it's getting to you.
Shit gets to me too, you know,
나에게도 그런다네, 내가 원하는 방향으로
주어 담고 뱉어 놓고.....
but I take it in, I let it out
on my own terms.
I bet you didn't write
one word down
틀림없이 자넨 프로스키 박사가 준
작은 공책에 한 글자도 쓰지 않았을 거야
in that little notebook
Prosky gave us.
Of course not. Did you?
물론 안 했지, 자넨 했나?
Yeah, it's great.
응, 괜찮더군
It helps me put things in perspective.
나에게 도움을 줘
올바르게 쓰더군......
You know what I'm saying?
Write it down, get it out.
뭔 말인지 알겠나?
글을 쓰게나, 그리고 털어 놔
- You should try this.
- Let's have a look.
- 한번 해 보게나
- 내가 함 볼께
What, are you kidding me?
Oh, come on, come on.
This belongs to me... private.
이건 나만의 것이네, 사생활
- You don't want to let me see?
- Close to my heart. No, sir.
- 안 보여 줄텐가?
- 이건 내 심장일세 절대 안돼
I just got sick
of the whole fucking game...
속이고, 단서들을 찾고, 체포를 하는
이 모든 게임에 넌더리가 난다
run around looking for clues,
making arrests,
write reports, testify, cut deals.
보고서를 쓰고, 증명하고, 짜 마추고,
이 모든 게임이 엉터리지
It was all just so much
fucking bullshit.
Detective...
형사님...
Then it all got real simple.
그러면 속기 쉬운 현실이 되겠지
Yeah, Detective Perez here.
Hey, brother, what's up?
응, 페레즈 형사
이봐, 레일리, 왜 그래?
I hate scumbags. I like shooting people.
What was I giving up?
난 쓰레기 같은 놈을 증오한다,
쏴 죽이고 싶고, 내가 왜 포기 했을까?
Perez: Hey, look, I set the meeting up
with Rooster first thing tomorrow.
저기, 내일
루스터 선배하고 만나기로 했네
Come on, you gotta be fast, man.
I don't want Turk getting wind of anything.
그래, 말은 잘하지
터크 선배가 아무것도 몰랐으면 하네
A retirement party and a gold watch?
은퇴 기념 파티? 금 시계? 시장과 악수?
명판에 내 이름 새기는 것?
A handshake from the mayor
and my name on some fucking plaque?
Big fucking deal.
그딴게 다 뭐야!
이것 보다는 낮겠지
It's better this way.
Now everybody knows
who I was and where I stood.
지금 내가 누군지, 내가 어디에 있는지
모두들 알겠지
Hey, it's me.
저기, 나야
Listen, I think somebody
followed me here... home.
일단 들어, 누군가 날 미행해
지금은 집이야
He's outside right now.
지금 밖에 있어,
당신........
Can you come over or...?
...이쪽으로 올수 있는지.....
다시 전화 줘, 알았지?
Just call me back, okay?
All right.
알았어
Don't move.
- Come on, open up.
- Turk?
어서, 문 열어
터크
I just called you.
- 방금 전화 했어
- 총 내려놔
Put the gun down.
There's a car following me.
- 저기 날 미행한 차가 있었어
- 총 내려놔! 총 내려놔
Put the gun down.
Have you got
something to tell me?
- 나에게 할 말 없어?
- 뭘?
About what?
Trager, Randall.
- 트래거, 렌달 사건.....
- 당신 내 아파트에 몰래 들어왔군...
Did you sneak
into my apartment?
What are they doing
on your computer?
당신 컴퓨터에 그게 다 뭐야?
I was checking
all the links in the case.
그 사건에 모든 연관성을
조사하던 중 이였어
Are you hiding something
from me?
당신 나에게 숨기는 거 있지?
Huh?
I just received this... this poem.
방금 이걸 주웠어, 시야
A poem?
Not worth mentioning, huh?
시? 그걸 언급하셨군, 하아?
The handwriting
doesn't even match.
필적이 일치하지 않아
이건 가짜야
It's a fake.
Did you write it?
그럼, 당신이 썼지?
당신이 쓴 거지?
Did you write it?
What the hell is going on here?
이러는 이유가 도대체 뭐야?
You're spending a lot of time
with Perez, aren't you?
당신은 페레즈와
너무 많은 시간을 보내, 안 그래?
Yeah, I've been working the case.
맞아, 우린 사건을 조사 중이잖아
What, are you jealous?
- 당신.., 질투하는 거야?
- 당신을 믿어도 돼?
Can I trust you?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- 그래
- 좋아
Get me anything and everything
that you can find out
페레즈와 레일리에 대해 발견한 게 있으면,
어떤 것이라도 나에게 알려줘.....
about Perez or Riley,
what they know about me.
...그들은 날 알거야
Everything.
모든 걸, 카렌
날 물먹이지 마
Karen, don't play me.
Hingis: I am leaning much further
into saying that it is a cop.
전 당신이 주장한 "그 범인은 경찰이다"
너무나 서투는 증거를 배우고 있습니다
Perez: Tell you what... I'm moving
past the leaning stage
저기, 선배 잘 들어요,
이 몸은 배움의 단계를 통과했죠,
물론 경찰의 활동 무대도
분명히 알고 있습니다....
and I'm moving towards the
l-know-for-sure-it's-a-fucking-cop stage,
considering how expertly
he shot the shit out of my house.
내 집에서 총을 쏜 경찰을
고려하면 말이죠
Hingis: Oh my God.
Are you hurt?
오 맙소사, ..., 자네 다쳤나?
Am I hurt? Am I hurt?
He wants to know if I'm hurt.
다쳤죠..., 다쳤죠,
내가 다친 걸 선배가 알고 싶어하네
Actually, he's dead.
사실은 죽었어요
- Rooster: His name is Magulat.
- Turk: The guy we saw at Salerno's.
그의 이름은 메갈랏 이였네
- 그날 밤, 우리가 경마장에서 본 남자
- 맞아
Yeah, he's in intensive care
at St. Luke's.
루크 거리에서 발생한
강력 사건에 그가 있었지
They think he's the guy
그들은 메갈랏이 "야코브 프로스티"의
머리를 잘라냈다고 생각하네
- chopped off Yakov Pearlstein's head.
- What do you think?
자네 생각은 어떤가?
자넨 그가 "희생자" 또는 "용의자"라고 보는가?
You think he's a victim,
or could he be our suspect?
I don't know, but either way
I think it's gonna be fun.
어느 쪽인지 잘 모르겠네
재미있어 질 것 같은데...
Doctor, what's the story?
의사 선생님,
어찌 된 사연이죠?
He's one of the toughest human beings
I've ever come into contact with.
이 남자는 제가 수술해 본
인간들 중에 신체가 넘버원 입니다
We took six bullets
out of him.
- 6개의 총알을 끄집어 냈죠
- 6개?!
Six? Whoo!
Three from the night he was wounded,
three from previous shootings.
3방은 그날 밤에 난 상처고,
다른 3방은 전에 맞은 총알이죠
The man is a tank.
이 남자 탱크에요
Do you mind if I talk to him
a little bit?
그와 잠깐 이야기 해도 되죠?
His jaw's wired shut,
but go ahead.
- 그의 턱은 짧죠, 이야기 해 봐요
- 알겠어요
That's okay. I'll ask the questions.
He can just grunt.
제가 질문을 할 땐,
그냥 으르렁만 거렸죠
Hey, Yevgeny.
이봐, 정신 차려
일어나봐, 완전히 정신을 잃어버렸군
Wake up.
That's it. Wake up,
you big fucking grizzly bear.
You don't speak Russian?
제가 러시아어로 말해야 하나요?
Swoboda. Swoboda. Swoboda.
Ron.
I'm thinking this Russian killing machine
could be our first eyewitness.
이 러시안 킬링 머신이
저희 첫 번째 목격자가 되겠죠
Wake up, gugumuck.
You can tell us who did this to you.
일어나봐, 메갈랏
누가 자네에게 이 짓을 했는지 말해 보게
- Detective, I think that's enough.
형사님, 이제 그만하세요
Then you could tell us where you put
Yakov Pearlstein's head.
자네 "야코브 프로스티"의 머리를
어디에 숨겼는지 우리에게 말해봐
4-4, 4-4, I need a round-the-clock
security detail
43, 43, 총격 사건의 정확한 시간이
어떻게 되는지....
on a patient Magulat,
M-A-gulat,
환자 이름은 메갈랏, M-A, gulat
루크 거리의 ICU (의학 집중 치료실)
St. Luke's in the ICU.
♪ I wake up in the morning... ♪
Is this the number to call
to report a case of police brutality?
경찰의 "잔혹 행위"를 신고 할려는데
이 번호가 맞나요?
- Cat got your tongue?
- Out on bail again?
응답이 없네
다시 보석금을 낼려고? 자넨 날 무서워 하는군
개노무 새끼, 뭘 원하는데?
What, you think you can scare me,
little bitch? What do you want?
Be careful, Detective.
My taxes pay your salary.
몸 조심해, 형사,
당신 월급이 내 세금이니.....
You don't pay any fucking taxes,
you lowlife piece of shit.
넌 세금도 안내는 새끼야,
넌 그냥 개노무 새끼일 뿐이야
- Get to the point, come on.
- One of your vics, Trager,
요점이 뭐야, 말해봐
희생자들 중에 한명인, 트래거은
남쪽에서 모든 총을 훔쳤지
stole a whole lot of guns
down South.
Same guns are turning up
on your murder scenes.
같은 총들이
당신 살해 현장에 나타났지
So it's simple...
그럼 간단해, 누가 총을 빼돌렸는지 알아봐,
쉽게 찾을테니..
find stolen guns,
you got your guy.
So you know the guy?
그럼 자네가 범인을 안다고?
Do you know if there's a cop out there
who might be a danger to the public?
물론, 내가 거래 할려는 경찰은
시민들에게 위험할지도 모르지
I couldn't live with myself
if I just stood by and didn't say anything.
난 내 자신을 믿고 살지
어떠한 속담도 귀담아 듣지 않을 뿐이지
Look, I'm gonna give you
two seconds more. Give me yes or no.
이봐, 2초를 더 줄테니,
"네" 또는 "아니오"라고 대답해
Do you know the guy?
And when do I meet you to talk about it?
범인을 안다고?
언제 만나면 되겠는가?
Friday, 9:00 PM, at my club.
- 금요일 9시, 내 클럽에서...
- 알겠네
I'll be there.
Man, there's dumb
and there's dumber,
멍청하군, 멍청해,
이런 멍청한 새끼가 이리로 오다니
but this is the motherfucking dumbest
right here, man.
Easy, son, easy.
It's gonna be easy for you.
진정해, 진정해
자네에게 일이 쉽게 풀리겠군
All you gotta do is be bait, that's all.
Be a little sardine for us, all right?
자네는 미끼를 잘 던졌네, 바로 그거야
우리에게 약간만 부추기면 돼, 알았나?
You help us... we got you covered.
Your club doesn't get hassled
우릴 도와준다면,
우리가 자넬 지켜 주지
자네 클럽은 온 종일 시달리지 않을 걸세
사건에 관련이 없을테고, 감옥도 가지 않을 걸세
and you don't have a revolving door
in and out of jail.
Do we have a deal or not?
거래를 할 건가? 말 건가?
Yeah, but your boy come in here
and go Hannibal Lecter on my ass,
좋아, 자네 동료가 여기에 오면
하니발 렉터(살인마)의 똥구멍을 햛을 줄 알아
I don't want no Jodie fucking Foster
coming through the door.
조디 포스터가 저 문을 통해서
들어온다 해도, 난 모르는 일이야
I want the goddamn
Marine Corps, man.
하나님이 총인종을 눌려도 말야
♪ Since Color Me Badd was singing
"I wanna sex you up"...♪
Evening, Detective.
안녕하세요, 형사님,
하나 드실래요?
You want one? It's shit,
but it's better than nothing, right?
맛이 없겠지만,
없는 것 보다는 낮겠죠?
Turk's voice: As soon as I heard
the fucking Russian didn't die
난 러시아인이 죽지 않았다는
소리를 듣는 즉시
I knew things would never
be the same.
모든게 같을 순 없다는 걸
나도 알고 있다
I had to change the rules,
규칙을 변경해야 겠다, 전략적으로
the strategy.
I had to be bold, do something
that could never be undone.
대담하게 해야겠다...,
원상태로 돌아갈 일은 절대 없을 것이다
I went for the unforgivable.
난 용성할 수 없는 일을 했다
No. Please. No.
제발, 안돼.....
Karen over phone: Did you hear
anything I just said?
뭔 말인지 모르세요?!
방금 말했잖아요!!
How exactly could I be
blowing this out of proportion?
제가 얼만큼 더 크게 불어서
떠벌려야 하죠?
That psycho just assaulted me.
그 정신병자가 날 습격했어요!
I am telling you
he is a classic sociopath.
그 놈은 "반 사회적 정신병자"에요
Okay okay,
I'll look into it, all right?
알았네, 알았어, 조사하겠네
알았나? 조사 할께
I'll look into it.
You stay the hell away from here.
Understood?
지금 그곳에서 나오게
알았나? 알았나?
Understood?
Fuck that.
집어쳐
Man: Check the ball,
check the ball.
I got the ball. I got the ball. I got the ball.
Stay on him. Stay on him.
Karen: Excuse me,
I'm Detective Corelli.
실례합니다, 아주머니, 형사 코렐리에요
예약 좀 확인 할께요
- I need to see your reservation book.
- Woman: Sure. Help yourself.
물론이죠, 보세요
"맥 데이비드 피쉬"
- Thank you.
- Anytime.
- 고마워요
- 천만에요
Yes, this is Detective Corelli.
네, 코렐리 형사에요
I've been trying to reach
Detectives Perez and Riley
페레즈와 레일리 형사
위치를 찾고 있어요
and I can't seem
to locate them.
그들 소재가 불분명해서요 / 알겠어요
- Perez: I like to party.
- That's nothing. I was into Kiss.
- 난 파티가 좋아
- 난 부비부비와 키스가 좋아
I used to run
around the house
with my tongue hanging out,
spitting fake blood.
내 혀는 목이 마르면,
가짜 피를 뱉지
I need to speak to them
urgently.
그들과 긴급한 통화를 해야 합니다
Yes, I understand,
but I need the location, please.
네, 압니다, 근데 제가...,
위치 좀 알려주세요, 제발
Hey, he's here.
저기, 터크 선배가 왔어요
Turk: Let me in.
들어가게 해줘
Thank God it's the police.
아 고마워라! 그 경찰놈이 왔네
Yeah, so where do we go?
- 자 왔네..., 어디를 가면 되나?
- 절 따라와요
Follow me.
I used to play ball
a couple of blocks from here.
- 여기서 2블럭 된 곳에서 야구를 하나?
- 그곳에는 볼 일이 없수다...
Get the fuck out of here.
When I was a kid I wasn't afraid
to mix it up with guys like you.
난 어렸을 때도,
자네 같은 새끼들을 겁내지 않았지
You still ain't.
아직도 그래요
Yeah, nowadays
I carry a gun with me.
지금은 카렌이 나와 함께 사는데,
나쁜 이웃이지
It's a bad neighborhood.
- It ain't bad for me.
- Yeah, well...
- 저에게는 아닙니다
- 그런가
Yeah, he's inside.
네, 안으로 들어갔어요
Well, so far so good.
지금까지는 좋아요
So now that we're done with
the pleasantries, what do you got for me?
아양 떠는 일 그만하게
Rooster: He's talking.
- 어서 빨리 말하게?
- 좋군, 얘기를 하고 있군
- What did you think he was gonna do?
- Spider: How about an apology?
그가 할 거라고 보나?
Spider: The shit that happened to Stubby,
that wasn't supposed to happen.
오! 반장님, 이 새끼는 쓰레기에요
- Rooster: Lieutenant, that's a crock of shit.
- I lost three fucking teeth that day.
그 날 내 이빨이 3개가 날라갔죠
He's not a civilian.
He's a fucking dealer.
그는 시민도 아니고,
빌어먹을 마약 거래상이죠
- And I kept my mouth shut.
- So what?
그래서 뭐? 자네들은
황금 이빨을 사랑하니, 나한테 고마워 해야지
You guys love those stupid gold teeth.
You should thank me.
Well, he's wearing a vest
and Starsky and Hutch here
터크는 러닝셔츠를 입었어요, 그리고 죽이
맞는 "영구와 땡칠이"가 감시하고 있죠
are watching him like a couple
of hawks... gay hawks.
- 멍청한 새끼들
- 네, 엿 먹으세요, 선배
- Yeah, right there, buddy.
All right, enough bullshit.
So you know our poetry boy?
알았네, 허튼소리는 집어 치우세
자네가 "시를 쓴 소년"을 알고 있다는데,
뭘 가져왔는지 보따리를 풀어보게
Just talk to me.
What do you got for me?
- All right, here we go.
- Here we go.
- 좋았어, 지금 시작 합니다
- 지금 시작해
Would you please?
제발 좀..?
Just 'cause the guy's talking tough,
that don't mean shit.
터프하게 말했을 뿐이네,
괜찮구만.....
Let me ask you something,
Copernicus.
뭐 좀 물어보죠, 코퍼닉 선배
That gun on his belt...
do you think it's a service pistol?
선배 벨트에 있는 총은...,
바로 소형 권총 아닌가요?
I bet you we'll trace it back to Trager's.
What do you think about that?
트래거 사건에 그 총을 사용했던데,
그건 어떻게 생각하죠?
- What do you want to bet?
- 500 bucks.
내기 하기를 원하는 겐가?
- 400달러요
- 그러지 뭐
- You're on.
- I'm in for another five.
- 전 500달러 걸죠
- 허, 이거 재밌군
Oh, this is fun.
Look, I help you,
you reciprocate.
- 봐요, 도와 줄테니, 보답을 해줘요
- 그럼, 날 도와
So help me.
All right, you might see
a little bit of a cell-phone video.
알았어요, 제 휴대폰 비디오 안에
그날 밤 당신이 쏜 트래거를 녹화해뒀어요
I got it in front of Trager's
the night he bought it.
- You got what?
- I got a movie...
- 자네가 뭘 했다고?
- 녹화한 게 있어요
a couple of kids back from the prom,
preserving their special memories,
무도회에서 돌아 온 꼬마들이
특별한 선물들을 가지고 왔는데,
a positive ID of you, big time.
순진한 생각으로,
형사님 보고 "Big Tom" 이래요
- Oh, yeah? Of me?
- Yeah.
- 오, 내가?
- 네
Okay.
좋아
Now you know
what I'm talking about.
- 지금 제 말 뜻이 뭔지 알죠?
- 알겠네
Yeah, now I got it.
Yeah, well,
so how do I look?
그래, 내가 그리 보이던가?
Like a poet?
시인 처럼?
'Cause that's what I am,
you know, a poet.
- 왜냐하면 그게 나니깐, 난 시인이야
- 잡았어요, 어서 갑시다
All right, come on, let's go.
In fact, I wrote a poem for you, Spider.
Want to hear it?
사실, 자네를 위한 시를 이미 준비했네,
스파이더 듣고 싶은가?
Eh?
Drop your gun right now, motherfucker!
Drop to the ground right now!
총 내려놔요, 어서요!
어서 내려놔!
Oh! Oh! Grease me up and...
- 어서 빨리!
- 오, 나에게 은총을...
국가가 2개의 여분으로 더 주거나 하겠지?
I mean, do they actually pay
you two morons?
- Put the fucking weapon on the ground.
- Gladly. Gladly. Right there.
- 땅에다 그 빌어먹을 총 내려놔
- 기꺼이, 기꺼이 주지
Right there. There you go.
여기 있네
Hey, you want to read my poem?
- 내 시를 읽고 싶나?
- 진정, 진정해
Easy easy.
Here, read it.
자 여기, 읽어요
"You tried to set me up, you fucks,
넌 날 함정을 파놨지, 개놈새끼들
이런 식으로 말이야
And this is how you do it?
You thought I'd get
my dick cut off,
넌 내가 속고 있는줄 알았지만,
대신 넌 정말 얼빠진 짓을 원하는 군
Instead you only blew it."
- Great stuff.
- What is that shit?
- Thank you.
- 훌륭했어 - 저게 뭐야?
- 고맙네
That is poetry.
그건 시야
What are you doing here?
자네 여기서 뭐하는 겐가?
Well, don't look at me, partner,
날 보지 말게나, 파트너
자넬 보호하기 위해 혼자서 술래잡기 했네..
but I tagged along
to protect your ass
and to see the look on their faces.
It was worth it.
...저놈들의 얼굴을 보기 위해서 왔지
가치가 있었어
We're doing our jobs here, okay?
I'm not gonna apologize for that.
저기, 저희는 일을 한 것 뿐이에요,
전 사과하지 않을 겁니다
I never want you to apologize, Teddy.
There's a killer out there with a badge.
나도 원치 않네, 테디
그곳엔 배지를 단 살인자가 있네
- What are you morons doing about it?
- What do you think we're doing here?
자넨 대충 때우러 이곳에 왔는가?
- 우리가 왜 이곳에 왔다고 보는데요?
- 그거 아주 좋은 질문이야
- That's not it.
- No, that's not it.
- 터크 선배가 아니야
- 맞아, 아니지
I just made 1000 bucks.
나 방금 1천 달러 벌었네
Where's the other gun?
Give it to me.
저기...다른 총은 어디에 있나요?
어서 내놔요, 어서요
Why don't you frisk me, Sherlock?
Go ahead.
옷 위로 몸수색하지 말게, 셜록 홈즈
어서, 수색해
- Frisk me, go ahead. Go ahead.
- Yeah, I'm gonna frisk you.
- 어서, 수색해
- 수색하고 싶지 않아요
어서 해
Ooh, nice touch, Mary.
조심하게, 메리
일을 한 후에 자넨 뭐하는가?
What are you doing after work?
Unless you're committed.
I don't want to get
in the middle of anything.
자네가 전념하지 않으면,
난 중간에 포기할 마음은 없네
What happened to your face?
Your mick friend give you a little love bite?
자네 얼굴에 그게 뭔가?
자네 하녀 친구가 사랑의 펀치를 날렸나?
- Shut the fuck up. Shut your fucking face.
- Hey hey hey! Whoa!
입닥쳐!
얼굴을 뭉개 버릴라!
I'll blow your brains out
if you don't get the fuck away.
니 얼굴에 한방 날려 줄테야! 개놈아
저리 꺼저!...
- What's he talking about?
- What he's talking about is,
저 놈이 뭔 소리를 하는 거야?
그가 이야기 한 것은 바로 "이번 사건에
우리가 찾던 용의자가 아니란" 말이죠
just 'cause you didn't go for this
doesn't mean you're not our guy.
- Now we gotta break this shit up.
- Don't translate for me, man.
저희는 이제 그만 할테니..
그만해
Rooster: Will you let this go?
You fucked up, okay?
- 얼간이 처럼 행동하지 말라고
- 터크 선배가 욕을 하잖아요.....
- We fucked up 'cause you helped him.
- I'm gonna nail your ass.
- 엿이나 처 먹어
- 겪어 보니깐 어때요, 선배?
I'm not through with you, man.
Make a mistake.
- 선배 실수한 거요
- 이 짓을 그만뒀으면 하네
Rooster: I'm gonna
break this stuff down, okay?
You fucking dog.
개 호로 새끼야
Relax, Spider.
긴장풀어, 스파이더
이리오게, 한자 하게나
Come on, let's have a drink.
I saw what I think
is a refrigerator here.
바로 이곳에
냉장고가 있는 걸 봤는데
I'll be back in a second.
잠시 후에 다시 올께
Hey, muffinhead.
이봐, 미련퉁이
Is this the person
who shot you?
이 남자가 당신을 쐈죠?
You're sure?
확실하죠?
No, you're the pumpkinhead.
아니, 네가 미련곰탱이지
You miss me?
내가 그리웠어?
"...of death and pain,
Place oneself among the slain.
If one addiction goes unfed,
The world is better with him dead."
Take it easy.
- 진정하게
- 괜찮네, 모든게 괜찮아질 거야
It's okay.
It's gonna be all right.
Jesus Christ, Rooster.
- 하느님 맙소자, 루스터 자네...
- 난 방안에 들어왔을 뿐이네
Just move into the room. Here.
Sit down. Sit down.
앉게
앉아!
Okay.
You gotta know about this,
Tom, from me.
자넨 이 일을 알거야, 톰...,
나에 대해서 말야
Now just open that little book,
start reading.
작은 수첩을 열어서
읽기 시작했지
Everything you want to know
is in there.
자네가 알고자 하는게
그 수첩에 다 있네
So go ahead.
그러니, 읽게
Out loud.
큰 소리로........
For the record.
녹화 중이군
See the little video here?
여기 미니 카메라 보이지?
"My name is David Fisk,
Detective First Grade.
내 이름은 데이비드 피쉬
강력반 형사
I've been a cop in the NYPD
for nearly 40 years."
난 거의 30년 동안 뉴욕경찰국에 몸 담았다
- Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave.
- Tom,
- 데이브, 데이브,...
- 그래, 뭘?
we've got a lot to cover
and not much time to do it in, so...
톰, 우린 많은 걸 은폐했네
이러고 있을 시간이 많지 않네,
그러니...
"My name is David Fisk,
Detective First Grade."
내 이름은 데이비드 피쉬
강력반 형사
My name is David Fisk.
내 이름은 데이비드 피쉬
"I've been a cop in the NYPD
for nearly 40 years."
난 거의 30년 동안 뉴욕경찰국에 몸 담았다
I don't expect you
to remember me.
당신이 날 기억하리라
예상 못했지
I mean, it's been a long time
날 당신 무릎에 앉힌 그 날이
후로 오랜 시간이 지났군요
since you sat me on your lap
and told me you loved me.
...당신이 날 사랑한다는 그 말...
"In that time
현재는....,
I've killed 14 people."
제가 14명을 죽였어요
Rooster: But I guarantee
장담하컨대,....
you're gonna remember the name
for the rest of your life.
당신은 그 이름을 기억 할겁니다...
남은 생애를 이런 일을 하면서...
"You don't become a cop
because you want to serve and protect.
자넨 자기 목적을 채우거나
주장하기 위해서 경찰이 된 게 아니군
You join the force because they let you
carry a gun and a badge.
자네에게 총과 배지를 주었기 때문에
자넨 그 힘을 즐거워 하는군
Most people respect the badge.
대부분 이들은 배지를 존경하지
또한, 총도 존경심을 불러 일으키지
Everybody respects the gun."
I'm the killer.
I show up at your door.
난 살인자네, 보여줬고
문을 향해 발포했지
Turk: What are you talking about?
It's not a fucking chess game.
자네 뭔 소리를 하는 겐가?!
이건 체스 게임이 아닐세!
Who knows? Maybe it is.
You're making all the wrong moves.
혹시 아나, 그거 일지도 모르지.....
자넨 잘못된 수를 둔 거네
I'm gonna put two
through his fucking head
연장으로 그 놈의 대가리를
쑤셔 넣겠네.....내가 직접 말일세
myself.
I know it to a moral certainty.
틀림없이 해야되는 일이지
You sort of get numb to it.
일종에 감각이 무더지더군,
감각이 무더져............
"Tom Cowen was my role model.
톰 코완, 그는 내 마누라였다(파트너)
The day I stopped trying to be him
내가 "톰 코완 이기를 포기했던 그 날"이
내 인생에서 최고의 날이였다
was the greatest day of my life.
Several years back I framed
a lowlife child killer
몇년 전에, 어린이 살해범
"찰스 렌달"인 그 자식을 죽이기로 작정했다
named Charles Randall.
I should have known
it would come back to haunt me."
나에게 다시 출몰할 것 같았다
What do you want me
to do with this?
자네..,
이것으로 내가 뭘 하기를 원하는데?
Is that all you got to say?
지금까지 말한 게 다야?
I owe you this explanation, pal.
자네에게 속죄를 하겠네, 친구
Why are you telling me now?
왜 지금 그 얘기를 하는건가?
Lvan the Terrible
is gonna wake up pretty soon
총 맞은 "이반",
그는 곧 있으면 깨어날 걸세
and he's gonna ID me.
그리고 날 지목하겠지
Evening, Detective.
안녕하세요, 형사님
하나 드실래요?
You want one? It's shit,
but it's better than nothing, right?
맛이 없겠지만,
없는 것 보다는 낮겠죠?
I can just walk right in here.
Your partner's asleep. Step outside.
내가 이곳에 방금 들어왔을 땐,
"프로스키" 박사는 잠자네...나가게, 어서
Did I ever pick
the wrong fucking Russki to shoot?
내가 엉뚱한 러시안 새끼를
쏜게 잘못된 거라고 보나?
Now we're going off the record.
이제 우린 녹화가 되지 않을 걸세
Uh, I'm going to take the rap
for the Randall gun thing.
아, 난 자네가 "렌달"에게 죄를
뒤집어쓰기를 원했네, 자네도 봤잖는가
You saw that.
I mean, considering
the circumstances, why not?
그 상황을 고려할 때, 왜 안 되겠어?
나에게 고마워할 필요는 없네
No need to thank me.
That business about not being me...
- 이걸 나에게 뒤집어 씌우진 않겠지?
- 그럼
Yeah.
I don't get that.
못 믿겠어
Well, you're a great cop, Tom.
자넨 훌륭한 경찰이야, 톰
I mean, you were the one
자넨 내 인생에 있어서 유일한 산소였지,
두번 다시는 없을 거야
I aspired to all my life
and could never be.
Then you broke the law,
그리고 자넨 범을 어겼네
planted the gun on Randall,
총에 관해 위증했지.....
렌달에 대해서...
let me down.
......날 실망시켰지
I lost my faith.
난 신앙을 버렸네
That's when it all started.
모든 일이 시작할 때,
그리 됐지
And once it did,
그리고 자네가 한번 했을 때도...,
난 멈출 수가 없었네
I couldn't stop.
Finally,
마지막으로...,
난 원하지 않았네
I didn't want to.
So I did my own thing.
허나, 그럴수 밖에 없었지, 알잖은가?
마지막에는......
And you know what? In the end
it got done.
죄를 뒤집어 씌우는 거지
정액들을 배출하는 거지
The scum went down.
And that's it. That's that.
그러는 거지, 그거야....
I don't understand
a word you said,
뭔 소리를 하는지 모르겠네
- don't understand any of it.
- I know you don't, Tom.
- 뭔 말인지 이해를 못...
- 자네가 이해를 못하는 걸 아네, 톰
As soon as I heard
the Russian didn't die
러시안 놈이 죽지 않았다는
소식을 듣는 즉시,
I knew I had to change the rules,
내 규칙을 변경해야 했지,
"미완성의 일을 끝마쳐야겠다"라고 말야
do something that could
never be undone.
난 용서할 수 없는 짓을 했지
I went for the unforgivable.
No.
So what am I gonna do, my friend,
그럼 내가 뭘 해야겠나?
내 친구, 동료인 자네를 체포할까?
partner? Arrest you?
At some point I gotta call it in.
동료들을 불러야 할일 생겼군
We're a team.
- 우린 팀이야
- 그랬었지
We were.
Yeah, we were, a great team.
그래, 그랬었지
- 훌륭한 팀이지
- 그건 어제까지야, 데이브
That was yesterday, Dave.
Today...
오늘은...
today you're pointing a gun at me.
오늘은 자네가 날 겨냥하고 있었어
But it hasn't gone off yet.
총 울림은 아직 끝난게 아니네
Bye, Tom.
- 잘가게, 톰
- 어딜 가는데?
- Where are you going?
- I don't know.
모르겠네, 지옥에나 가겠지
To hell, I suppose.
- Hey, Dave, Dave.
- Whoa.
이봐, 데이브
Don't come closer!
가까이 오지마!
- You wouldn't.
- You want to bet your life on it?
- 그래선 안 되네
- 자네 인생에 도박을 걸고 싶은가?
Come on, partner, I know you.
You wouldn't.
그러지 말게, 파트너
자네가 하지 않을 거라 믿네
But I would.
내가 할 거야
Oh.
Karen, just take it easy.
카렌, 진정해
- Can't get me out of your mind?
- Shut up, Dave.
- 당신의 마음을 잊어도 되겠죠?
- 닥치게, 데이브
You're gonna defend
this lowlife piece of shit?
당신...., 당신이 변호하는 이 새끼는...
....비열한 쓰레기야!
- Boy, I'm in your head.
- I'm not defending him. Take it easy.
- 생각하기 나름이지...
- 난 저 놈을 쏠겁니다
Fuck you, Turk.
Put the gun down, Fisk.
- 진정 하라고!
- 엿 먹어, 터크, 총 빨리 내려놔!
- And if I don't?
- Dave.
- 하지 않겠다면?
- 데이브
- How about I blow your brains out?
- Ooh, I like the sound of that.
당신 머리를 날려 버리는 건 어떨까?
- Don't move.
- Karen.
꼼짝마!
You blow me away, Turk dies.
Is that your idea?
- 카렌
- 날 날려 버리면, 터크는 죽어
- 그러고 싶은가 보지?
- 움직이지 말라고 말했지, 넌 쓰레기야
I said don't move, you prick.
Bye-bye!
Give me the gun.
총 줘봐, 나에게 총을 줘
Stay here.
이곳에 있어
Oh, man.
오, 이런!
Fuck.
젠장!
- These old locks...
자물쇠들이 오래돼서 잠겼어
I mean, they're good.
- 정말 안 좋군
- 데이브, 우린 이 일을 끝마쳐야 하네
Dave, you've got to end
this thing.
End it?
- 끝내자고?
- 총이나 내려 놓으세
Put the gun down.
What's your plan?
자네 계획이 뭔데?
날 체포 할려고?
Are you gonna arrest me?
Are you gonna take me down
to the precinct, book me,
날 감옥에 쳐 넣을게 아닌가,
지문을 채쥐해서 기록할 게 아닌가?
fingerprint me,
body-cavity-search me?
몸 수색하고, 날 조사하고?
뭘 어떻게 할려고 이러는데?
What the fuck
are you gonna do?
헬랄도에서 날 돌아다니게 할려고?
1주 일에 "마약 중독자"를 보여주거나...
Wheel me out on the "Geraldo" show,
a freak of the week?
Or better yet, an in-depth
psycho profile on "Oprah"?
오프라 쇼에"심층 심리학" 보여줄려고?
Are you ready for that?
It ain't gonna fly, man.
자넨 준비가 되었나 보지?
난 날고싶지 않네, 친구
Dave, you give me no choice.
데이브, 자넨 선택의 여지가 없네
You got a choice... I escape.
자넨 선택했네, 난 벗어날 걸세
날 그리해 줄 수 있는가, 톰?
Would you do that for me, Tom?
- 날 벗어나게 해 주겠냐 이 말일세, 톰?
- 제발, 그러지 말게나
Would you let me escape?
Come on, don't do this.
I'm gonna make a run for it.
난 도망갈 걸세
어떻게 생각 하나?
What do you think?
You gotta do the right thing.
옳은 선택을 하게
10:10이네, 파트너
방아쇠를 당기고, 용의자가 된 느낌
That's a 10-10, partner...
shots fired, suspect fleeing.
Let's go!
Come on, don't go there.
- 하자고!
- 제발, 그리 하지 말게나
Hey, partner, come on.
Shots fired.
이봐, 파트너, 어서!
방아쇠를 당겨
- Don't do this.
- Suspect fleeing,
- 이러지 말자고!
- 용의자가 된 느낌, 체포에 불응하고?
resisting arrest. Come on.
어서!
A righteous man
정의로운 남자...,
내가 취하기 전에......
Before me stands,
A hero in these filthy lands.
이 불결한 땅에 서 있는 한 영웅
A brother in arms,
마음속에 있는 전우가 자네인가?
In heart are you.
I was really hoping
자네도 그리하기를 정말 원했었네
You'd get it too.
- I do get it.
- No, you don't.
나도 그리 하겠네
- 아니, 자넨 못해
- 아냐, 나도 할께
No, I get it.
You know, the only thing
in this life
이 인생에 있어 단 한 가지는 말야.....
that ever gave me
any satisfaction
나에게 만족을 주는 것이였네...
was killing those fucks.
그 새끼들을 죽이는 거 말일세
So this is for real.
그래, 이것이 인생이라네
I mean,
단..., 이 경우는 아니지
this one is bad.
10-14.
10-13, 경찰이 쓰러졌네
Officer down.
I ain't going anywhere, Tom.
아무데도 안 가겠네, 톰
아무데도 가지 않을 걸세
I ain't going anywhere.
It's okay.
괜찮네
4-4 squad, Central.
34 본부 지원센터, 34 본부 지원센터....
10-14, officer down.
184th and St. Nick's.
10-13 경찰이 쓰러졌다, 니클라스 거리 184번지
경찰이 쓰러졌다, 10-13...긴급함
Officer down, 10-14.
Hurry hurry hurry.
- Dispatcher: 10-4, 4 squad...
- Tom, don't. Don't.
- 10-4, 니클라스 거리 184번지 확인했다
- 톰, 하지말게
- Officer down. ETA six minutes.
- Don't.
6분 정도 소요된다.....
Don't.
하지말게...
4-4 squad, Central.
- 34 본부 지원센터
- 네, 말씀하세요
Dispatcher: Central.
Go ahead, 4 squad.
That's a 10-55 on the bus.
Cancel the ambulance.
- 10-55이다, 앰블런스를 취소하겠다
- 10-5?
Dispatcher: 10-5?
앰블런스를 취소하겠다,
10-55, 앰블런스를 취소하겠다
Turk: Cancel the ambulance.
10-55 on the bus. Cancel the ambulance.
- You sure on that?
- Sure on that.
- 확실 합니까?
- 확실하다
You did this, you know.
- 자네가 이 쇼를 했네
- 아네, 파트너, 알어
I know, partner, I know.
We did good, Tom.
우리 좋았지, 톰
Tom, Tommy.
톰
말해보게
We did good. We did good.
우린 좋았지
자넨 좋은 사람일세, 톰
You're a good man, Tom.
You're a good man.
자넨 좋은 사람이야
I wish you...
바라네...
I wish you
난 자네가...
continued success.
화려한 성공을 하길 바랬네
Some piece of work, your partner.
- 곤란한 일을 했군요, 파트너
- 불을 켜세요
Lights.
Look, Cowen,
보세요, 코완, 우리는 그 시 살인자가
"피쉬"형사라고 예상했죠
the way we see it,
Detective Fisk just closed the door
on the poetry boy.
알겠수, 어찌되었던...,
당신들이 무슨 말을 하던.....
Good. Whatever you say.
Are we done?
- 끝 마쳤나요?
- 네, 끝났습니다
Yeah, we're done.
Turk's voice: My daughter called.
내 딸은 "루스터" 사건에 당황을 했고,
나에 대해 걱정을 했다
She was upset about Rooster
and worried about me.
She asked me if I was likely
to do something stupid
내가 만약 그였다면, 그런 멍청한 일을
하겠냐고 반문을 했다
and I said, "Like what,
난 대답을 했지, "뭘 말야?"
take anger management classes
or retire?"
성질 죽이기 수업에 들어가거나?
퇴직을 하라고?
I said I was gonna do
the same old thing I always do.
난 말했지, 내가 항상 하던
그 일을 할 거라고.......
She said, "Good.
What else could you do?"
딸이 대답하길 "좋아요",
그거 아니면 다른 일을 하겠나요?
I said, "Right."
난 대답했지
"맞아, 부전자전이지, 내 딸아"
A real chip off the old block,
my daughter.
딸이 대답하길,
아빠도 좋은 경찰이죠
She said I was a cop
and a good one.
Funny... Rooster said
the same thing.
재밌어, "루스터"도 똑같이 말했는데...
Turk: Okay, guys,
let's get ready to play ball.
저기, 얘들아, 실전 같이 해
On the count of three.
Everybody in?
셋을 셀테니...
모두 준비됐지?
One, two, three, explosion!
원, 투, 쓰리
예!
감사합니다 -배찌-